<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Salmond on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/alex-salmond/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alex Salmond on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:57:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/alex-salmond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A lose-lose proposition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-lose-lose-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-lose-lose-proposition/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, following the widely covered announcement of Alex Salmond&#39;s new Alba party, those who listened very closely would have heard two distinct sounds: a pained groan and a jubilant celebration. For the SNP, it was a knife thrust deep into their back, and for Unionists, it was the joy of watching an enemy devour itself. Alba&#39;s hype — that it will somehow game the system and end up with an unchallengeable majority — is the ravings of a vindictive and ego-driven man high on his own supply.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: The SNP framed Salmond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</guid>
      <description>In a livestream broadcast on All for Unity’s (the new name for Alliance for Unity) social media channels, George Galloway doesn’t mince his words when talking about the Sturgeon-Salmond scandal.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Comparing Sturgeon’s government to a banana republic, he starts by talking about the malicious fraud prosecution of administrators over the Rangers bankruptcy by the Crown Office.&#xA;£24 million of Scottish taxpayers money is about to be paid out because of a malicious prosecution mounted by the Scottish Law officer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salmond: &#39;Nicola needed a stake through my heart&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/salmond-nicola-needed-a-stake-through-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 17:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/salmond-nicola-needed-a-stake-through-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>Today, Craig Murray, who is on trial for contempt of court, accused with revealing the identities of Salmond&#39;s accusers, submitted evidence in his defence. Extracts of his major revelations follow...&#xA;Read the full statement here&#xA;After a preamble about his background as an ex-ambassador, diplomat and author, Murray says:&#xA;&#39;9. I discovered with a high degree of certainty that the leaker was Liz Lloyd, Chief of Staff to Nicola Sturgeon.&#39;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salmond: ScotGov’s document withholding is ‘contempt of court’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/salmond-scotgovs-document-withholding-is-contempt-of-court/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 21:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/salmond-scotgovs-document-withholding-is-contempt-of-court/</guid>
      <description>Today, Alex Salmond’s submission to the Holyrood inquiry was released in unredacted form (link). In it, he says that his legal team has identified 46 documents out of nearly 400 that were released by The Scottish Government that neither he, nor his legal team, had previously seen. He says that many of these would have been ‘crucial’ to both the Judicial Review and his criminal trial. Salmond says the documents, which the Scottish Government not only have a duty to disclose, but also failed to disclose, despite a search warrant, would have reinforced the Judicial Review’s review of bias, not just of the Investigating Officer, Judith Mackinnon, but of the Permanent Secretary, Linda Evans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon: Bigotry in a Smart Suit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was talking to a female ex-Labour supporter, and new Nationalist. While claiming she was &#39;for social justice&#39;, she said that she was all for anyone being Scottish, except for JK Rowling. When I asked why, she told me that Rowling should be excluded because of her political views. Whatever you think of Ms Rowling, or transgender activism, this woman, who presumably thinks she is a decent person, told me straight up that someone with a different political opinion from her has no place in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
