<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark Devlin - The Majority Publisher on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mark-devlin---the-majority-publisher/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mark Devlin - The Majority Publisher on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 20:35:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mark-devlin---the-majority-publisher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Majority View: Open our beer gardens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-view-open-our-beer-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 20:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-view-open-our-beer-gardens/</guid>
      <description>The words &#34;Beer Garden&#34; and &#34;Scotland&#34; are not often heard together, but they have sparked a storm in Scotland as Nicola Sturgeon has refused permission for them to open for another two weeks, despite giving earlier indications that they could open now. Why not?&#xA;We were told from the beginning that the purpose of the lockdown was to save the NHS being overwhelmed. Even at the height of the crisis, the NHS, staffed by our amazing carers, was never in any real danger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon: Bigotry in a Smart Suit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was talking to a female ex-Labour supporter, and new Nationalist. While claiming she was &#39;for social justice&#39;, she said that she was all for anyone being Scottish, except for JK Rowling. When I asked why, she told me that Rowling should be excluded because of her political views. Whatever you think of Ms Rowling, or transgender activism, this woman, who presumably thinks she is a decent person, told me straight up that someone with a different political opinion from her has no place in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Not A &#34;Unionist&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/why-im-not-a-unionist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/why-im-not-a-unionist/</guid>
      <description>One of the main techniques extremist groups like Nationalists use to make themselves appear normal is to label their opponents something they would like them to be and then attack that label.&#xA;By labelling their opponents as “Unionists” or “Yoons” they associate them with Union Jacks, British bulldogs, Churchill, and The Queen.&#xA;(Of course the Union that the Nationalists almost always imagine is English — they never include Northern Ireland or Wales, or the Scottish people who are part of Britain.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
