<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Brexit on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/brexit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Brexit on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:26:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/brexit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The SNP has no respect for democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-no-respect-for-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-no-respect-for-democracy/</guid>
      <description>There is a parallel universe where the SNP respects democracy.&#xA;In this alternative world in 2014, post referendum, Alex Salmond and Nicola Sturgeon acknowledged that two million people in Scotland had voted for Scotland to remain part of the United Kingdom and that the 10% winning margin —&amp;nbsp; which meant 24% more people voted NO than YES — was clear and decisive.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;To show their acceptance and heal the wounds of the divisive, “once-in-a-generation” referendum, three days after the referendum, they attended the service of reconciliation which the Church of Scotland had organised at St Giles Cathedral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: Three Reasons Against Separation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-three-reasons-against-separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 22:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-three-reasons-against-separation/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MfzzO_9YN9k&#xD;It’s only been a few weeks since George Galloway announced his return to Scottish politics, with the aim of taking on Scottish Nationalists in the 2021 Scottish elections. In that time, he has formed a new party @Alliance4Unity, which has gained over 7400 Twitter followers in a week, and received over 1800 letters from would-be candidates (which he says he is having some difficulty processing).&#xA;Today, he appeared live on YouTube and Twitter&amp;nbsp;to discuss his views and his new party, citing three main reasons he opposes Separation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
