<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Devolution on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/devolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Devolution on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 19:25:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/devolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>There is no ‘Union Dividend’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/there-is-no-union-dividend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 19:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/there-is-no-union-dividend/</guid>
      <description>So called pro-UK politicians from both the Conservatives and Labour often trumpet the &#34;Union dividend&#34; — the extra billions Scotland receives from the United Kingdom — as proof that staying in the UK benefits ordinary Scots. On paper, the numbers seem impressive: according to the Government Expenditure and Revenue Scotland (GERS) 2024–25 report, Scotland receives £2,669 more per person in public spending than the UK average.&#xA;But in reality, this dividend is wasted as under the SNP, Scotland’s extra funding is being squandered on a bloated, inefficient, and politically motivated public sector, while schools, hospitals, and local services continue to decline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pincer Movement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/pincer-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/pincer-movement/</guid>
      <description>The United Kingdom faces a persistent challenge from separatist movements, particularly in Scotland, where the Scottish National Party (SNP) has pursued independence with unrelenting focus. Despite the intentions behind devolution, the existence of devolved legislatures like Holyrood has amplified the separatist agenda rather than diminished it. To secure the UK, a pragmatic dual strategy—a short-term defense and a long-term solution—is required.&#xA;The Failure of Devolution to Quell Separatism&#xD;When devolution was introduced, proponents like Labour politician George Robertson claimed it would &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are NOT ‘stuck with’ devolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-are-not-stuck-with-devolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 18:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-are-not-stuck-with-devolution/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the 25th anniversary of the first session of The Scottish Parliament. As expected, a host of insiders, including Scottish Labour politicians, are saying they are proud of what has been achieved, while Scots wonder if those politicians – who are almost all receiving a salary from the Scottish Parliament – have somehow missed the past 25 years.&#xA;So let’s cast our minds back to 1997 and ask the question that is not being asked: What if legislative devolution was not part of New Labour’s manifesto, and it never happened?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to be cheerful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/reasons-to-be-cheerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 22:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/reasons-to-be-cheerful/</guid>
      <description>It’s an often repeated theme of anti-UK nationalism (the SNP in Scotland especially) that there is a popular demand from the UK public to break up the UK. They bleat repeatedly in a monotone like sheep ‘The Union is dead’ in a sad attempt at creating the impression that the UK will inevitably break up. They have to maintain this fiction as any look at the objective, verifiable, empirical facts (data and statistical evidence) gives the conclusion that in ALL parts of the UK, a clear and often substantial majority of the public want to keep the UK together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reform or Abolish?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/reform-or-abolish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 17:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/reform-or-abolish/</guid>
      <description>The final part of The Majority&#39;s three-part series on the failure of Scottish Devolution and the options to reform or abolish the Scottish Parliament. Part 1 – How we got here&#xA;Part 2 – Power Grabs, Waste &amp;amp; Scandal The first part of this series covered how legislative devolution grew from a concept into the reality of the Scottish Assembly, and talked about how, rather than acting as a bulwark against nationalism, it has become a UK Government-funded vehicle for nationalism and constitutional division.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Grabs, Waste &amp; Scandal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/power-grabs-waste-scandal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 20:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/power-grabs-waste-scandal/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of a three-part series on the failure of Scottish Devolution and the options to reform or abolish the Scottish Parliament. Part 1 – How did we got here?&#xA;Before a system can be fixed or abolished, we need a clear understanding of the problems and issues of the current system of Legislative Devolution:&#xA;Constitutional conflict&#xD;Centralisation&#xD;Excessive spending&#xD;Lack of accountability&#xD;Constitutional Power Grabs&#xD;It is a well-known fact that political organisations always aim to expand their power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scotland&#39;s devolution disaster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/scotlands-devolution-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 14:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/scotlands-devolution-disaster/</guid>
      <description>It’s been 25 years since the devolution experiment was inflicted on Scotland, and the result is an unspeakable disaster. It’s a disaster because The Scottish Parliament, which was set up to stop Scottish Nationalism, is now being abused by the SNP to promote a separatist agenda, while Scotland’s services decline daily and scandal mounts up. And it is ‘unspeakable’ because few want to discuss whether the source problem is devolution itself, even its natural opponents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>John Mortimer: It&#39;s time to abolish Holyrood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/john-mortimer-its-time-to-abolish-holyrood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 20:24:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/john-mortimer-its-time-to-abolish-holyrood/</guid>
      <description>With six months to go to the Holyrood elections, Mark Devlin talks to John Mortimer, of the Abolish The Scottish Parliament Party, about the party’s progress and goals. What is the aim of the party?&#xA;The party’s flagship policy, of course, is to abolish the Scottish Parliament, which we consider to be a divisive waste of money. We believe that the £100 million running costs each year would be better spent on health and education, and that the powers and funding that the Scottish Government has centralised in Edinburgh, should be returned back to local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devolution has failed: Abolish Holyrood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/devolution-has-failed-abolish-holyrood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 12:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/devolution-has-failed-abolish-holyrood/</guid>
      <description>How much does it cost to change a lightbulb at Holyrood?&#xA;A few quid perhaps? Maybe ten or twenty quid at a stretch? No… in fact it turns out it costs £357 to change a lightbulb at the Scottish parliament building. Some £1.75 Million was spent on upgrading lights in the devolved assemblies’ debating chamber in 2016-7, working out at an astonishing £357 apiece.&#xA;That same year, costs ranged from £25.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
