<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GERS on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/gers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GERS on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 17:25:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/gers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Independence Is Dead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/independence-is-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 17:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/independence-is-dead/</guid>
      <description>This week, John Swinney launched yet another desperate push to try to break up the UK, this time fronted by a glossy poster declaring:&#xA;“Scotland is a nation. We affirm that every nation has the right to choose its own future. We choose a future where Scotland decides its own government…This is our plea, our right, and our opportunity: To place who live here at the heart of our national opportunity: democracy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop lying about GERS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-lying-about-gers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 18:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-lying-about-gers/</guid>
      <description>With the SNP’s conference now taking place, shortly after the annual Government Expenditure and Revenue Scotland Report (GERS) has just been published, now is an ideal time to stop nationalists&#39; lies and misdirections and their dismissals about the state of Scotland’s finances.&#xA;These dismissals follow the same forms:&#xA;GERS is produced by the UK Government to discredit Scotland GERS does not give a real picture of Scotland’s finances These are followed by two self-serving arguments:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When leaders lie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-leaders-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 21:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-leaders-lie/</guid>
      <description>It is often said in these post-truth times, that a lie has gone half-way around the world before the truth has put its boots on. Why do lies, fake news and misinformation gain so much more political traction than evidence-based facts? The answer to that question can be found in the world of tribal epistemology.&#xA;In 2017, David Roberts of Vox news coined the term ‘tribal epistemology’ to describe a state of mind ’where you believe not what facts or reason or top experts say is true, but what your group or tribe say is true, especially its leaders’.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
