<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jamie Blackett on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/jamie-blackett/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jamie Blackett on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 20:51:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/jamie-blackett/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Polls, insults and manifestos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/polls-insults-and-manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 20:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/polls-insults-and-manifestos/</guid>
      <description>They say, with penetrating accuracy, that once you become a parent you are only as happy as your least happy child. And, sad to say, since we got the Alliance for Unity going last year it has been like having an extra child. The party’s triumphs and disasters have produced the same reaction in me as my children’s and I find myself worrying like a parent about our progress.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The anxiety to start with was not finding enough people of sufficient calibre to join us; then it was that the Electoral Commission would find excuses to keep turning down our application to be a political party until beyond polling day; then it was that we would simply be ignored by everyone; then it was that we would never feature in any polls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Act of Clarity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-act-of-clarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 14:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-act-of-clarity/</guid>
      <description>In an article in The Critic, Alliance for Unity’s Deputy Leader, Jamie Blackett, outlines eight ways which a UK Secession Clarity Act could clarify requirements before any secession referendum takes place. With many years before the next &#39;once-in-a-generation&#39; vote, Blackett argues that it makes sense to work out the rules in advance.&#xA;These rules would apply to any Scottish, Welsh or Northern Irish referenda and should be seen, not as roadblocks, but as paths to legitimacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Choice: Civilization or the Tribe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-choice-civilization-or-the-tribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 18:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-choice-civilization-or-the-tribe/</guid>
      <description>Four of the candidates who will be standing for the Alliance for Unity, in a bid to maximise the anti-Separatist vote in next May’s crucial Scottish Parliament elections, have delivered Monday evening broadcasts which can be found on You Tube.&#xA;George Galloway, Jamie Blackett, David Griffiths and Alan Sked spoke with clarity and conviction about their formative experiences. An ardent socialist, a conservative-minded businessman, a Leaver and a Remainer, as well as two supporters of Glasgow’s highly competitive football clubs, can be found among the four.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
