<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Douglas Ross on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/douglas-ross/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Douglas Ross on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/douglas-ross/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis but a scratch!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/tis-but-a-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/tis-but-a-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday, working-class voters in England gave a resounding vote of confidence in Boris Johnson and an incumbent Tory government. Just a few miles north, though, here in Scotland, the Scottish Tories barely managed to hold on to their seat total.&#xA;The Scottish Conservatives are valiantly trying to portray this as a win, but they’re like the Black Knight in Monty Python and the Holy Grail, on the ground with their legs and arms cut off, saying ‘tis but a scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run away! Run away!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/run-away-run-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/run-away-run-away/</guid>
      <description>On Thursday, I read an article by Adam Morris in the Independent (If Boris Johnson wants to save the Union, he should stay far away from Scotland) which seems to encapsulate the appeasement and cowardice of the so-called Scottish Conservative &amp;amp; Unionist Party. So, I thought I’d go through it line-by-line and highlight the loserthink it embodies.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Morris starts by trying to claim that the departure of Michelle Ballantyne is a gain for the party.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apples and Oranges</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/apples-and-oranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/apples-and-oranges/</guid>
      <description>Imagine two salespeople at your door. One sells apples, the other oranges. Both fruits cost the same.&#xA;The apple salesperson says, ‘Buy this apple, it’s tasty!’. The orange salesperson, worried at this simple message, tries a different approach, ‘You like apples? This orange is just like an apple’.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Which one are you most likely to choose?&#xA;If the orange salesperson doesn’t believe in their product, why should we? There are many selling strategies, but dissing your own product never works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Ross: A leader I believe in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/douglas-ross-a-leader-i-believe-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 13:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/douglas-ross-a-leader-i-believe-in/</guid>
      <description>I have never, under any leader, felt more positive about our chances of winning the next Holyrood Election.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;I believe Douglas Ross is a political nuclear weapon that can not only strike fear into the Scottish National Party, but can stabilise this country financially and restore the power to the people, from a centralist Government in Edinburgh.&#xA;Living in South Lanarkshire, for me, Edinburgh often feels 550 miles away from home, while London feels 30 miles away.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
