<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jamie&#39;s Election Diary on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/jamies-election-diary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jamie&#39;s Election Diary on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:18:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/jamies-election-diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fish &amp; chips and tactical votes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/fish-chips-and-tactical-votes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 23:18:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/fish-chips-and-tactical-votes/</guid>
      <description>Back on the trail. and I arrive on the seafront in Troon just as George is mounting the soapbox. Getting out of my car is a blessed relief. My little car was only ever designed to be a run-around and I have been bent double for two and a half hours, all the while imagining Douglas Ross, Anas Sarwar and Nicola Sturgeon sitting on their battle buses, sipping coffee and checking their Twitter timelines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sex toys, imposters and warm receptions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sex-toys-imposters-and-warm-receptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 13:06:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sex-toys-imposters-and-warm-receptions/</guid>
      <description>“You know there was no word for dildo in Gaelic until the SNP invented one? They have paid translators to come up with the full suite of words to cater for all sexual tastes.” The breadth of George’s grasp of current affairs never ceases to amaze me. We are blethering in a café in Stranraer on our soap box tour of the South of Scotland. This conflation of the SNP’s fake Gaelicisation, warped morality and waste of taxpayers’ money would have been a gift for opposition politicians and the media in most countries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaks, Tory shenanigans and cows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/leaks-tory-shenanigans-and-cows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 21:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/leaks-tory-shenanigans-and-cows/</guid>
      <description>I decided to do my bit for the television party political broadcast in a field with our dairy cows in the background. The sun is shining and, by chance, they are grazing one of the paddocks that has Criffel, the South of Scotland’s most beautiful mountain, in the background.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Gayatri (George’s wife) is behind the camera and despite being outside her comfort zone, gamely scrambles under the electric fence and gingerly picks her way in patent leather ankle boots between the cowpats to set up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polls, insults and manifestos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/polls-insults-and-manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 20:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/polls-insults-and-manifestos/</guid>
      <description>They say, with penetrating accuracy, that once you become a parent you are only as happy as your least happy child. And, sad to say, since we got the Alliance for Unity going last year it has been like having an extra child. The party’s triumphs and disasters have produced the same reaction in me as my children’s and I find myself worrying like a parent about our progress.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The anxiety to start with was not finding enough people of sufficient calibre to join us; then it was that the Electoral Commission would find excuses to keep turning down our application to be a political party until beyond polling day; then it was that we would simply be ignored by everyone; then it was that we would never feature in any polls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A week is a long time in politics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-week-is-a-long-time-in-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 21:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-week-is-a-long-time-in-politics/</guid>
      <description>“A week is a long time in politics” is a trite opening sentence but it has been true this week, as Salmond’s forced entry into the race has left things ‘all changed, changed utterly’ as WB Yeats wrote 105 years ago in a rather similar context. It is what we have feared all along: the formation of a ‘Nationalist Front’ and a creeping Ulsterisation of Scottish politics with Salmond already talking about ‘street protests’ as part of their campaign for secession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The campaign starts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-campaign-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 14:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-campaign-starts/</guid>
      <description>George Galloway and I launch our campaign by filming a ‘Potemkin rally’ in the pub carpark – all that we can do during lockdown.&#xA;We are met by the village loudmouth, ostentatiously masked by a black scarf against the Covid on the cold March breeze. “What’s going on here? Did you no see the saltires as you drove in? We don’t want you and your Union here.” He patrols the one street in the village while we are filming, just in case any ‘Yoons’ think about joining in.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
