<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tactical Voting on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tactical-voting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tactical Voting on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:02:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tactical-voting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Galloway Straight Answers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with Scotland Matters, The Majority presents a video interview series with George Galloway, covering his return to Scottish politics, his plans for Alliance For Unity, tactical voting and his views on Nicola Sturgeon. Watch them all.&#xA;#1 - Why have you come back to Scottish Politics?&#xD;https://youtu.be/iSLyTD9Cu1Q&#xD;#2 - Why is the UK important to you?&#xD;https://youtu.be/skM3XRzmCVc&#xD;#3 - Given your past causes why should people support you now?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tactical voting 2021: The basics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/tactical-voting-2021-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 15:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/tactical-voting-2021-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>The SNP are a MINORITY party that wins because the anti-Nationalist opposition vote is split three ways. Of the 73 constituency seats in the Scottish Parliament Elections, 59 are currently held by the SNP. That’s an astonishing 81% of seats from just 46.5% of the vote.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Talk about not getting the government you vote for! But how will tactical voting help? First we need to discard the two sets of seats where tactical voting won&#39;t make a difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An alliance for unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-alliance-for-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 15:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-alliance-for-unity/</guid>
      <description>Commentators on Scottish politics have tribal allegiances, just like the rest of us. They tend to be very dismissive of any new parties threatening to muscle in on the comfortable three-party opposition at Holyrood.&#xA;They cling to the dream that their preferred leader, Douglas Ross or Richard Leonard, is going to lead the long-awaited recovery in the Conservative or Labour vote and sweep the Nationalists from power, or that Willie Rennie will become kingmaker in any coalition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Have We Done To Deserve This?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-have-we-done-to-deserve-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 13:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-have-we-done-to-deserve-this/</guid>
      <description>Commentary by Jill Stephenson&#xA;First a couple of definitions.&#xA;‘We’ are the good, solid people of Scotland who voted to remain in the UK in 2014.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;‘We’ were relieved, rather than triumphalist, about having won the referendum.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;‘We’ didn’t rub the losers’ noses in it but tried to appease them. ‘We’ sat back and let the UK government make concessions to the side that had lost.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;‘We’ believed Salmond and Sturgeon when they repeatedly told us that the referendum was a ‘once in a generation’, ‘once in a lifetime’ event.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
