<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicola Sturgeon on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nicola-sturgeon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nicola Sturgeon on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nicola-sturgeon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>After the earthquake, a tsunami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/after-the-earthquake-a-tsunami/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/after-the-earthquake-a-tsunami/</guid>
      <description>It’s said that before a tsunami strikes there are major warning signs to look out for that should alert the public to the forthcoming catastrophe. Warning signs such as an earthquake at sea, or the tide suddenly going out, are usually enough to galvanise the inhabitants of neighbouring coastal towns to immediately head for the high ground.&#xA;Political tsunamis have striking similarities to the real thing. For example, there were many early warning signs before the 2015 General Election that alerted all pro-UK parties in Scotland to the very real possibility that they were going to be swept away by a gigantic nationalist tidal wave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pull up. Pull up.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/pull-up.-pull-up./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/pull-up.-pull-up./</guid>
      <description>Like many of us who now find ourselves locked inside for most of the day, I have been watching more movies than usual. A few nights ago, one struck me with its resonance to current Scottish politics. It was about an aircraft that, mid-flight, suffered a catastrophic malfunction to its tail assembly, causing it to roll over and enter a steep dive that inverted all of its controls; actions that would have previously lifted the nose of the aircraft would only push it down further.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway Straight Answers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with Scotland Matters, The Majority presents a video interview series with George Galloway, covering his return to Scottish politics, his plans for Alliance For Unity, tactical voting and his views on Nicola Sturgeon. Watch them all.&#xA;#1 - Why have you come back to Scottish Politics? https://youtu.be/iSLyTD9Cu1Q #2 - Why is the UK important to you? https://youtu.be/skM3XRzmCVc #3 - Given your past causes why should people support you now?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
