<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Majority - Press Release on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/the-majority---press-release/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Majority - Press Release on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:34:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/the-majority---press-release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Majority launches crowdfunded #ResignSturgeon billboards in Glasgow and Edinburgh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-launches-crowdfunded-%23resignsturgeon-billboards-in-glasgow-and-edinburgh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:34:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-launches-crowdfunded-%23resignsturgeon-billboards-in-glasgow-and-edinburgh/</guid>
      <description>Today, The Majority, with the support of over 150 donors who contributed to a crowdfunding campaign, launches its 2023 #ResignSturgeon billboard campaign, which comprises eight billboards in Glasgow and Edinburgh (see location list below).&#xA;CLICK HERE TO DONATE TO THE CAMPAIGN NOW&#xD;The campaign is a simple and direct message to Nicola Sturgeon to take responsibility for her catastrophic handling of the Scottish Government.&#xA;Mark Devlin, founder of The Majority:&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Majority launches STOP WASTING OUR TIME &amp; MONEY, BIN YOUR PRETENDYREF crowdfunded billboard campaign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-launches-stop-wasting-our-time-money-bin-your-pretendyref-crowdfunded-billboard-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 09:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-launches-stop-wasting-our-time-money-bin-your-pretendyref-crowdfunded-billboard-campaign/</guid>
      <description>Today, The Majority, with the support of donors who contributed to its crowdfunding campaign, launches the STOP WASTING OUR TIME &amp;amp; MONEY, BIN YOUR PRETENDYREF campaign to coincide with oral arguments at The Supreme Court by the Scottish Government, which has asked the Court to assess the legality of an advisory referendum on Scottish independence. The campaign includes digital billboards in Glasgow, and Edinburgh (locations in appendix).&#xA;The billboards also have a link to a new crowdfunding campaign, to fund further anti-PretendyRef billboards:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Majority launches SNP COUNCILS ARE RUBBISH crowdfunded billboard campaign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-launches-snp-councils-are-rubbish-crowdfunded-billboard-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 01:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-launches-snp-councils-are-rubbish-crowdfunded-billboard-campaign/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Our billboard campaign has been delayed. Apparently, the billboard company have a new policy that means direct criticism of political parties is not allowed (despite that being fine last year). We&#39;re submitting redesigned ads now.&#xA;UPDATE 2: We changed to a different company and the ads are now running, without any text changes&#xA;Today, The Majority, with the support of donors who contributed to its crowdfunding campaign, launches the SNP COUNCILS ARE RUBBISH #BinTheSNP campaign for the upcoming Scottish Council Elections on May 5.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Years of Failure. Get them out. #VoteTactical</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/14-years-of-failure.-get-them-out.-%23votetactical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 10:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/14-years-of-failure.-get-them-out.-%23votetactical/</guid>
      <description>Today, The Majority, with the support of almost 600 donors who raised £14,500 for their Let’s Put Up Billboards! crowdfunding campaign, launches its final elections campaign, before the Scottish Elections on May 6.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;After a hugely successful campaign that flew a #ResignSturgeon banner over Holyrood, and took ‘We Don&#39;t Believe You NIcola’ ad vans to the Scotttish Parliament, The Majority now takes the fight directly to the Scottish people, via billboards and mobile digital ad vans carrying a message highlighting 14 Years of SNP failure and promoting tactical voting:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Don&#39;t Believe You Nicola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-dont-believe-you-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 09:44:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-dont-believe-you-nicola/</guid>
      <description>Today, The Majority, with the support of over 480 donors who raised £12,000 for their Let’s Put Up Billboards! crowdfunding campaign, launches the second stage of its #ResignSturgeon campaign, in a series of campaigns leading up to the Scottish Elections on May 6. After a hugely successful campaign that flew a #ResignSturgeon banner over Holyrood and saw #Resign Sturgeon billboards appear across Scotland, The Majority now takes the fight directly to Nicola Sturgeon’s constituency in Govanhill, Glasgow and to the Scottish Parliament in Holyrood, using mobile digital ad vans carrying the message, ‘We don’t believe you Nicola’ and ‘#ResignSturgeon’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#ResignSturgeon campaign launches across Scotland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/%23resignsturgeon-campaign-launches-across-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 09:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/%23resignsturgeon-campaign-launches-across-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Today, The Majority, with the support of Scotland Matters, UK Union Voice and over 250 donors who contributed to a crowdfunding campaign, launches the #ResignSturgeon campaign, the first in a series of campaigns leading up to the Scottish Elections on May 6. The campaign starts with:&#xA;Three digital billboardsGlasgow - Clydeside Expressway (access near Lidl on Castlebank St)Edinburgh - Slateford Road (next to Jewson)Aberdeen - Market Street (at Union Square)</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
