<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alliance for Unity on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/alliance-for-unity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alliance for Unity on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 03:57:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/alliance-for-unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: The SNP framed Salmond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</guid>
      <description>In a livestream broadcast on All for Unity’s (the new name for Alliance for Unity) social media channels, George Galloway doesn’t mince his words when talking about the Sturgeon-Salmond scandal.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Comparing Sturgeon’s government to a banana republic, he starts by talking about the malicious fraud prosecution of administrators over the Rangers bankruptcy by the Crown Office.&#xA;£24 million of Scottish taxpayers money is about to be paid out because of a malicious prosecution mounted by the Scottish Law officer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway Straight Answers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with Scotland Matters, The Majority presents a video interview series with George Galloway, covering his return to Scottish politics, his plans for Alliance For Unity, tactical voting and his views on Nicola Sturgeon. Watch them all.&#xA;#1 - Why have you come back to Scottish Politics? https://youtu.be/iSLyTD9Cu1Q #2 - Why is the UK important to you? https://youtu.be/skM3XRzmCVc #3 - Given your past causes why should people support you now?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An alliance for unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-alliance-for-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 15:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-alliance-for-unity/</guid>
      <description>Commentators on Scottish politics have tribal allegiances, just like the rest of us. They tend to be very dismissive of any new parties threatening to muscle in on the comfortable three-party opposition at Holyrood.&#xA;They cling to the dream that their preferred leader, Douglas Ross or Richard Leonard, is going to lead the long-awaited recovery in the Conservative or Labour vote and sweep the Nationalists from power, or that Willie Rennie will become kingmaker in any coalition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: Salmond’s fat arse, Bun fights at the OK Corral, and The Mother of All Scandals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-salmonds-fat-arse-bun-fights-at-the-ok-corral-and-the-mother-of-all-scandals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 20:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-salmonds-fat-arse-bun-fights-at-the-ok-corral-and-the-mother-of-all-scandals/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CcIPr3AOGhQ In his weekly broadcast, George Galloway, leader of the fledgling Alliance For Unity Party, covers many of the issues in Scottish politics today. We have transcribed the best parts for you.&#xA;#1 Significant Labour figure to join Alliance For Unity We are building a stable of parliamentary candidates that are really thoroughbreds and I can&#39;t tell you who right now, but I have been talking for the last day or two to a very prominent twice Labour party parliamentary candidate about joining us on the lists for the Holyrood elections in May.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Choice: Civilization or the Tribe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-choice-civilization-or-the-tribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 18:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-choice-civilization-or-the-tribe/</guid>
      <description>Four of the candidates who will be standing for the Alliance for Unity, in a bid to maximise the anti-Separatist vote in next May’s crucial Scottish Parliament elections, have delivered Monday evening broadcasts which can be found on You Tube.&#xA;George Galloway, Jamie Blackett, David Griffiths and Alan Sked spoke with clarity and conviction about their formative experiences. An ardent socialist, a conservative-minded businessman, a Leaver and a Remainer, as well as two supporters of Glasgow’s highly competitive football clubs, can be found among the four.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey to Alliance For Unity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/my-journey-to-alliance-for-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 12:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/my-journey-to-alliance-for-unity/</guid>
      <description>Did you hear the one about the lifelong Rangers fan who spoke to George Galloway and decided to work with him to help redefine the Scottish political landscape?&#xA;It’s not a joke, it’s exactly what happened to me two weeks ago.&#xA;Until this time, I had never interacted with George Galloway and had never felt any wish to do so. From nowhere, a series of tweets appeared from the former MP, urging pro-UK political parties to form an alliance to defeat the SNP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: Three Reasons Against Separation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-three-reasons-against-separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 22:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-three-reasons-against-separation/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MfzzO_9YN9k It’s only been a few weeks since George Galloway announced his return to Scottish politics, with the aim of taking on Scottish Nationalists in the 2021 Scottish elections. In that time, he has formed a new party @Alliance4Unity, which has gained over 7400 Twitter followers in a week, and received over 1800 letters from would-be candidates (which he says he is having some difficulty processing).&#xA;Today, he appeared live on YouTube and Twitter&amp;nbsp;to discuss his views and his new party, citing three main reasons he opposes Separation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
