<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to Fight on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/how-to-fight/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to Fight on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 11:55:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/how-to-fight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What about Whataboutery?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-about-whataboutery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 11:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-about-whataboutery/</guid>
      <description>To highlight what the other side has done is one of the commonest forms of evasion of personal moral responsibility&#34; --&amp;nbsp; Cardinal Cahal Daly&amp;nbsp; In my previous article for the Majority, I spoke about how nationalism and nationalists rely on paradoxes to both validate their own opinions and dismiss the facts of others. It is time, therefore, to dissect and discredit their preferred technique, &#34;whataboutery&#34;, or the Scottish version, &#34;whitabootery&#34;. Simply put, whataboutery serves two functions, firstly to try to put the person who asks the question on the defensive, and secondly to allow the person using whataboutery to deflect away and avoid answering the question asked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be The Pig: A primer on how to fight Nationalists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/be-the-pig-a-primer-on-how-to-fight-nationalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 09:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/be-the-pig-a-primer-on-how-to-fight-nationalists/</guid>
      <description>To my fellow anti-Nationalists: With the deepest of respect, you&#39;re doing it wrong.&#xA;Every day, I see people arguing on Twitter, trying to counter Nationalist arguments. One thread I&#39;ve been following on Twitter has literally hundreds of responses trying to convince Nationalists that they are wrong about Scotland’s finances. Of course the Nationalists are wrong.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;But has all that discussion done any good? No. Has anyone been converted? No. Has it taken the fight back to them?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
