<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicola Sturgeon on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/nicola-sturgeon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nicola Sturgeon on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:57:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/nicola-sturgeon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A lose-lose proposition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-lose-lose-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-lose-lose-proposition/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, following the widely covered announcement of Alex Salmond&#39;s new Alba party, those who listened very closely would have heard two distinct sounds: a pained groan and a jubilant celebration. For the SNP, it was a knife thrust deep into their back, and for Unionists, it was the joy of watching an enemy devour itself. Alba&#39;s hype — that it will somehow game the system and end up with an unchallengeable majority — is the ravings of a vindictive and ego-driven man high on his own supply.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A matter of gravity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-matter-of-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 22:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-matter-of-gravity/</guid>
      <description>Time is a unique concept; it is a variable constant that has come to dominate everyone&#39;s lives on this planet. Be it by the sun&#39;s movement and the need to care for cattle or the morning commute to your 9-5 job, time impacts us all, but we experience it in different ways.&#xA;One concept is that of time dilation, where the passage of time is different in two bodies depending on the velocity at which they travel; think of the masterful movie&amp;nbsp;Interstellar, where the protagonist in space experiences time much slower than his daughter on earth so that when they meet again, he seems not to have aged at all while his daughter is on her death bed from old age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SNP has no respect for democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-no-respect-for-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-no-respect-for-democracy/</guid>
      <description>There is a parallel universe where the SNP respects democracy.&#xA;In this alternative world in 2014, post referendum, Alex Salmond and Nicola Sturgeon acknowledged that two million people in Scotland had voted for Scotland to remain part of the United Kingdom and that the 10% winning margin —&amp;nbsp; which meant 24% more people voted NO than YES — was clear and decisive.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;To show their acceptance and heal the wounds of the divisive, “once-in-a-generation” referendum, three days after the referendum, they attended the service of reconciliation which the Church of Scotland had organised at St Giles Cathedral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: The SNP framed Salmond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</guid>
      <description>In a livestream broadcast on All for Unity’s (the new name for Alliance for Unity) social media channels, George Galloway doesn’t mince his words when talking about the Sturgeon-Salmond scandal.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Comparing Sturgeon’s government to a banana republic, he starts by talking about the malicious fraud prosecution of administrators over the Rangers bankruptcy by the Crown Office.&#xA;£24 million of Scottish taxpayers money is about to be paid out because of a malicious prosecution mounted by the Scottish Law officer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salmond: &#39;Nicola needed a stake through my heart&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/salmond-nicola-needed-a-stake-through-my-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 17:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/salmond-nicola-needed-a-stake-through-my-heart/</guid>
      <description>Today, Craig Murray, who is on trial for contempt of court, accused with revealing the identities of Salmond&#39;s accusers, submitted evidence in his defence. Extracts of his major revelations follow...&#xA;Read the full statement here&#xA;After a preamble about his background as an ex-ambassador, diplomat and author, Murray says:&#xA;&#39;9. I discovered with a high degree of certainty that the leaker was Liz Lloyd, Chief of Staff to Nicola Sturgeon.&#39;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twilight of the idols</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/twilight-of-the-idols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 19:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/twilight-of-the-idols/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember, just a few months ago, when statues were being toppled around the world? Men who had been venerated in their time were now exposed as having profited from slavery or other ignominious acts. What was surprising was how quickly it all happened. One day nobody cared; the next statues were being pulled down. How quickly times change.&#xA;The esteemed German sociologist Max Weber says leaders, in the past or today, derive their authority from three different sources: legal authority, traditional authority, and charismatic authority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This tower will fall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/this-tower-will-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 19:14:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/this-tower-will-fall/</guid>
      <description>I used to play Jenga as a child, and I have always remembered how often the most stable-looking tower would crumble, when a single, seemingly unimportant block was removed. That tower reminds me of the current SNP, as Nicola Sturgeon and her cronies pull the blocks out from under themselves.&#xA;In a recent contribution to the Spectator it was noted that, despite the SNP and Nicola Sturgeon&#39;s woeful handling of a myriad of domestic issues, she and her party remain popular amongst Scottish voters, seemingly defying electoral and political gravity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sturgeon’s stepping stones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-stepping-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 18:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-stepping-stones/</guid>
      <description>It seems to me that there is a gap between presentation - very, very good presentation - and the reality. When it comes to Coronavirus data, when it comes to education, when it comes to the Alex Salmond issue. There is a gap between how you present yourself - very, very effectively - and what’s really been going on in Scotland.&#xA;Andrew Marr, questioning Nicola Sturgeon - 29th November, 2020 https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Freakery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/control-freakery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/control-freakery/</guid>
      <description>Last night, I published a video I had been forwarded of a group chat in which Nicola Sturgeon’s sister says that although Nicola is very tired she won’t delegate to her deputy because she is a ‘total control freak’.&#xA;https://twitter.com/themajorityscot/status/1318293732597399559 Personally, I think she needs a day or two off, and hand it over to her Deputy. But that&#39;s not Nicola, she&#39;s a total control freak. She wouldn&#39;t do that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola&#39;s Book Club</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicolas-book-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 17:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicolas-book-club/</guid>
      <description>Hello Majority fans, Wee Nicola here. As you know, I love books. I’m always reading books. Book, books, books! So here’s some of my favourites, hope you love them too... #NicolasBookClub...&#xA;My wee pal @KateForbesMSP wrote a great memoir about her work experience. #NicolasBookClub&#xA;I love how @lokiscottishrap tells us about the poor and disadvantaged. After Indy, he’ll have a lot more of that to write about… #NicolasBookClub&#xA;And who doesn&#39;t love a good horror?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Education Blame Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-great-education-blame-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 22:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-great-education-blame-game/</guid>
      <description>The heart-breaking stories flooding social media yesterday, demonstrated a scandalous truth: that the life chances of many Scottish children are doomed, regardless of individual effort and ability. They evaporated the illusion of free will, the idea that through grit and determination you can transcend the disadvantages of multiple deprivation and poor schooling. The outcry has been predictable, from individual pupils and parents, politicians on all sides, and educationalists. The latter group warned months ago that the SQA moderation process was dodgy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five more ways Nicola Sturgeon has failed Scotland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-more-ways-nicola-sturgeon-has-failed-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-more-ways-nicola-sturgeon-has-failed-scotland/</guid>
      <description>The very first article on this site, Nicola Sturgeon’s five biggest failures, got a huge response, with over 14,400 views so far.&amp;nbsp; But, so many of you said ‘Only five..?’ And we agree, so here’s some more of our First Minister&#39;s failures. Share widely...&#xA;#5 Dude, where’s our superfast broadband? Lockdown measures over the last few months have really shown the importance of a reliable and fast broadband connection. In their 2016 election manifesto, the SNP proclaimed they would ensure “100% of premises across Scotland will have access to super-fast broadband by 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would you like a foot rub too, Nicola?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/would-you-like-a-foot-rub-too-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/would-you-like-a-foot-rub-too-nicola/</guid>
      <description>When will the opposition parties in Scotland learn to fight? Today I was appalled to see yet another weak and compliant message from Jackson Carlaw, leader of the Scottish Conservatives, praising the Nationalists for their response to COVID-19.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;https://twitter.com/themajorityscot/status/1278663688346570753 This comes on the heels of an earlier tweet where he did the same:&#xA;https://twitter.com/ScotTories/status/1247056001079095296 Confidence in the First Minister? W.T.A.F.&#xA;Jackson, a wee clue: they are not your friends. They are Nationalists who are destroying our country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon is ‘socially-distancing’ herself from Scottish parents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-is-socially-distancing-herself-from-scottish-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 15:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-is-socially-distancing-herself-from-scottish-parents/</guid>
      <description>In a previous contribution I wrote how the SNP have failed schoolchildren of all ages and stages of progress, with slipping standards. The Scottish Survey of Literacy and Numeracy (SSLN) found that only 49% of 13/14 year olds were performing &#34;very well&#34; or &#34;well&#34; in 2016, down from 55% in 2014 and 64% in 2012. It is against that backdrop that the SNP need a bolder drive and ambition to get Scottish school children all of the classroom time they can.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cult of St. Nicola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-cult-of-st.-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 21:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-cult-of-st.-nicola/</guid>
      <description>The camera shakes. A young child comes into view, the first of many, their gleaming eyes open and eager. They start talking in the coached manner of totalitarian regimes: The children of North Korea would like to say ‘thank you’ to our Dear Leader. We are so grateful, thank you for always keeping us safe, working so hard, for being strong for us. Thank you for caring for every individual life and for always thinking about the children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanted: a worthy opponent to Nicola Sturgeon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/wanted-a-worthy-opponent-to-nicola-sturgeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 17:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/wanted-a-worthy-opponent-to-nicola-sturgeon/</guid>
      <description>https://stephendaisley.com/2020/06/15/wanted-a-worthy-opponent-to-nicola-sturgeon/ Stephen Daisley, writing on his blog, says that frustration is rising as Scottish Nationalists fail to deliver results after 13 years in power.&#xA;Three terms of Nationalist rule have produced little of substance and on education and health we have seen progress stall and even go into reverse. Meanwhile, sizeable reserves of political capital, parliamentary time and government resources have gone into a constitutional war of attrition. What exactly about the past 13 years would make anyone want another five?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon: Bigotry in a Smart Suit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was talking to a female ex-Labour supporter, and new Nationalist. While claiming she was &#39;for social justice&#39;, she said that she was all for anyone being Scottish, except for JK Rowling. When I asked why, she told me that Rowling should be excluded because of her political views. Whatever you think of Ms Rowling, or transgender activism, this woman, who presumably thinks she is a decent person, told me straight up that someone with a different political opinion from her has no place in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon&#39;s Five Biggest Failures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeons-five-biggest-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 21:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeons-five-biggest-failures/</guid>
      <description>#5 She deprived 300,000 children of their new hospital Edinburgh&#39;s new Sick Children&#39;s Hospital was&amp;nbsp;supposed to open at the end of 2012.&amp;nbsp; You didn’t misread that: it&#39;s just one example of the level of incompetence we must live with under the SNP in Scotland.&#xA;The project has been so delayed it has even&amp;nbsp;outlived three previous health secretaries&amp;nbsp;who were looking after it, making Jeane Freeman the fourth. &amp;nbsp;I hear you all breath sighs of relief at that.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
