<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Original Content on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/original-content/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Original Content on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 15:39:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/original-content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon is ‘socially-distancing’ herself from Scottish parents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-is-socially-distancing-herself-from-scottish-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 15:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-is-socially-distancing-herself-from-scottish-parents/</guid>
      <description>In a previous contribution I wrote how the SNP have failed schoolchildren of all ages and stages of progress, with slipping standards. The Scottish Survey of Literacy and Numeracy (SSLN) found that only 49% of 13/14 year olds were performing &#34;very well&#34; or &#34;well&#34; in 2016, down from 55% in 2014 and 64% in 2012. It is against that backdrop that the SNP need a bolder drive and ambition to get Scottish school children all of the classroom time they can.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Majority View: Open our beer gardens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-view-open-our-beer-gardens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 20:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-majority-view-open-our-beer-gardens/</guid>
      <description>The words &#34;Beer Garden&#34; and &#34;Scotland&#34; are not often heard together, but they have sparked a storm in Scotland as Nicola Sturgeon has refused permission for them to open for another two weeks, despite giving earlier indications that they could open now. Why not?&#xA;We were told from the beginning that the purpose of the lockdown was to save the NHS being overwhelmed. Even at the height of the crisis, the NHS, staffed by our amazing carers, was never in any real danger.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Under One Braincell</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/all-under-one-braincell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 22:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/all-under-one-braincell/</guid>
      <description>On our daily trawl through the nether regions of Scottish twitter we came across this thread by @AOUBAlba. As you may recall, All Under One Banner organise pro-Separation marches for 99.99% of the Scottish population who stay home.&#xA;I&#39;ve been in chats with quite a few of these marchers who claim their Nationalism is &#34;civic and joyous&#34;. Yet is that really true? Yesterday, AUOB asked the question, &#34;What&#39;s the first thing that should be changed once Scotland regains independence?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cult of St. Nicola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-cult-of-st.-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 21:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-cult-of-st.-nicola/</guid>
      <description>The camera shakes. A young child comes into view, the first of many, their gleaming eyes open and eager. They start talking in the coached manner of totalitarian regimes: The children of North Korea would like to say ‘thank you’ to our Dear Leader. We are so grateful, thank you for always keeping us safe, working so hard, for being strong for us. Thank you for caring for every individual life and for always thinking about the children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five times Scottish Nationalists bullied the media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-times-scottish-nationalists-bullied-the-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 19:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-times-scottish-nationalists-bullied-the-media/</guid>
      <description>#5. The Sun pulled an article about the Health Secretary’s complacency…during a pandemic&#xD;Despite being months into the Coronavirus pandemic crisis, when frontline workers are still not being routinely tested and PPE shortages are still troubling, the Scottish Health Secretary, Jeane Freeman, had time in her schedule to tweet she would chase up ASDA for Nationalist journalist Angela Haggerty’s groceries.&#xA;This, rightly, attracted much scorn and derision. The Sun ran a perfectly legitimate article, which they then deleted, leaving little trace that this story ever existed - an airbrush job the Ministry of Truth would be proud of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon: Bigotry in a Smart Suit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was talking to a female ex-Labour supporter, and new Nationalist. While claiming she was &#39;for social justice&#39;, she said that she was all for anyone being Scottish, except for JK Rowling. When I asked why, she told me that Rowling should be excluded because of her political views. Whatever you think of Ms Rowling, or transgender activism, this woman, who presumably thinks she is a decent person, told me straight up that someone with a different political opinion from her has no place in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon&#39;s Five Biggest Failures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeons-five-biggest-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 21:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeons-five-biggest-failures/</guid>
      <description>#5 She deprived 300,000 children of their new hospital&#xD;Edinburgh&#39;s new Sick Children&#39;s Hospital was&amp;nbsp;supposed to open at the end of 2012.&amp;nbsp; You didn’t misread that: it&#39;s just one example of the level of incompetence we must live with under the SNP in Scotland.&#xA;The project has been so delayed it has even&amp;nbsp;outlived three previous health secretaries&amp;nbsp;who were looking after it, making Jeane Freeman the fourth. &amp;nbsp;I hear you all breath sighs of relief at that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Not A &#34;Unionist&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/why-im-not-a-unionist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/why-im-not-a-unionist/</guid>
      <description>One of the main techniques extremist groups like Nationalists use to make themselves appear normal is to label their opponents something they would like them to be and then attack that label.&#xA;By labelling their opponents as “Unionists” or “Yoons” they associate them with Union Jacks, British bulldogs, Churchill, and The Queen.&#xA;(Of course the Union that the Nationalists almost always imagine is English — they never include Northern Ireland or Wales, or the Scottish people who are part of Britain.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
