<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COVID-19 on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/covid-19/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COVID-19 on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 18:55:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sturgeon’s stepping stones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-stepping-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 18:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-stepping-stones/</guid>
      <description>It seems to me that there is a gap between presentation - very, very good presentation - and the reality. When it comes to Coronavirus data, when it comes to education, when it comes to the Alex Salmond issue. There is a gap between how you present yourself - very, very effectively - and what’s really been going on in Scotland.&#xA;Andrew Marr, questioning Nicola Sturgeon - 29th November, 2020&#xD;https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deadly Virus?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-deadly-virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 17:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-deadly-virus/</guid>
      <description>I have never been someone who has stuck to convention and blindly followed accepted normal practices, either in my work or, indeed, in my private life. Don’t get me wrong - I don’t break laws, but I am prepared to ‘think outside the box’ and look at things in a different way, if something doesn’t feel right. And I am not alone, as many of the great inventions and medical/scientific breakthroughs have happened because someone dared to look at things differently from the general population and the peers in their field.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Will Remember Them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-will-remember-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 12:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-will-remember-them/</guid>
      <description>This morning, Sunday 8th Nov, at approximately 1045hrs, I took the final steps to the Black Watch Monument that overlooks the Fintry area of Dundee. This act of remembrance to the fallen, has become a regular feature in my life for many years – missed only when I have been working overseas.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Under the grey skies, I paid my respects with other service veterans, while socially distancing. We refrained from shaking hands and hugging, but we Will Remember Them in the time-honoured fashion, regardless of the Scottish Government ban on gatherings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Five out of Ten’: Health experts slam Sturgeon’s COVID response</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-out-of-ten-health-experts-slam-sturgeons-covid-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 13:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-out-of-ten-health-experts-slam-sturgeons-covid-response/</guid>
      <description>In a video interview, conducted for Scotland Matters, on how an independent Scotland would have dealt with the Coronavirus crisis, leading health experts have slammed Nicola Sturgeon and the Scottish Government, rating their efforts as only ‘five out of ten’.&#xA;Due to constant TV exposure, the general public has a mostly positive view of Sturgeon’s handling of the crisis, and is favorably comparing Scotland’s perceived performance with that in England, despite similar infections and death rates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five more ways Nicola Sturgeon has failed Scotland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-more-ways-nicola-sturgeon-has-failed-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-more-ways-nicola-sturgeon-has-failed-scotland/</guid>
      <description>The very first article on this site, Nicola Sturgeon’s five biggest failures, got a huge response, with over 14,400 views so far.&amp;nbsp; But, so many of you said ‘Only five..?’ And we agree, so here’s some more of our First Minister&#39;s failures. Share widely...&#xA;#5 Dude, where’s our superfast broadband?&#xD;Lockdown measures over the last few months have really shown the importance of a reliable and fast broadband connection. In their 2016 election manifesto, the SNP proclaimed they would ensure “100% of premises across Scotland will have access to super-fast broadband by 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunak skelps the Nationalists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sunak-skelps-the-nationalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 21:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sunak-skelps-the-nationalists/</guid>
      <description>Commentary by Tommi Kerr.&#xA;On Wednesday afternoon, the Chancellor of Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, delivered a typically impressive performance in the House of Commons. Outlining the next phase of governmental support for the British people, he spoke passionately about protecting livelihoods before announcing an imaginative set of measures intended to kick-start the UK economy.&#xA;The&amp;nbsp;speech&amp;nbsp;– entitled ‘A Plan for Jobs’ – contained several notable soundbites. The measures themselves were eye-catching, with a floundering hospitality sector receiving special attention in the form of a VAT reduction and a new policy dubbed ‘Eat Out to Help Out’ – cue much innuendo on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola, close the Glasgow and Lanarkshire borders now!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-close-the-glasgow-and-lanarkshire-borders-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-close-the-glasgow-and-lanarkshire-borders-now/</guid>
      <description>Over the past 24 hours there&#39;s been quite a bit of discussion about closing the border from England, led by a shameless front-page headline in The National.&#xA;There&#39;s even a poll with over 5000 signatures that claims trips from England to Scoland are &#39;international&#39;...&#xA;There is about to be a massive second wave of this new virus in England due to Tory ineptitude. The borders of both Scotland and Wales should be closed to all but essential traffic ie commerce.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
