<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Independence on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/independence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Independence on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 17:52:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/independence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The SNP has never had a mandate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-never-had-a-mandate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 17:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-never-had-a-mandate/</guid>
      <description>It is a commonly touted assertion of the SNP that all elections, Westminster or devolved, will be referendums on independence and if they achieve a majority of some kind then this will give them a mandate for independence. But what does ‘mandate’ actually mean?&amp;nbsp;&#xA;A standard definition (via Google) of a mandate is:&#xA;The authority to carry out a policy, regarded as given by the electorate to a party or candidate that wins an election.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop the Neverendum: Ban secession now.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-the-neverendum-ban-secession-now./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-the-neverendum-ban-secession-now./</guid>
      <description>The UK Government should stop gambling with its territorial, economic, cultural and social integrity.&#xA;A couple of weeks ago, Alister Jack, the Secretary of State for Scotland, said that Scots could have a second ‘independence’ referendum if polls showed a consistent majority of 60% of Scots in favour of it. Gambling your country&#39;s future on the basis of opinion polls is certainly an interesting strategy, but, as I was getting ready to publish this article, the UK Government finally pushed back on Jack’s comments, saying, ‘We’ve never set a position on that.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
