<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/the-majority/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 20:07:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/the-majority/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An update from The Majority</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-update-from-the-majority/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 20:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-update-from-the-majority/</guid>
      <description>THE SHORT VERSION We won the battle, now to win the war. We’re working on lots of new projects and need your support. Please help us grow and continue our fight against ugly Scottish Nationalism with a monthly donation. Also, please sign our petition to get Newsquest and Gannet to cease publishing The National’s anti-English hate.&#xA;THE LONGER VERSION It is difficult to believe that it’s been almost two months since the drama of the Scottish elections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our response to The National bullying and intimidating our writers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/our-response-to-the-national-bullying-and-intimidating-our-writers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 18:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/our-response-to-the-national-bullying-and-intimidating-our-writers/</guid>
      <description>Two anti-Majority articles in The National today ( Expert’ Unionist vanishes after evidence query and Hundreds of active members of pro-Union group found to be fake ) serve no purpose other than to try to bully and intimidate us and our writers. They are not based on any news, but serve simply to say, ‘If you write articles against Scottish Nationalism, you will be targeted’.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Contrary to their claims, I have not received a single email or telephone call from the National asking for comment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help us build a strong anti-Nationalist media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/help-us-build-a-strong-anti-nationalist-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 22:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/help-us-build-a-strong-anti-nationalist-media/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/0rjSBnVLaUs It’s difficult to believe that it’s only been four months since I started the Majority. At the time, I was amazed that there was no media that represented us, the silent majority of anti-Nationalists in Scotland.&#xA;In four months, thanks to your support, The Majority has grown to over 8000 Twitter followers and 2500 Facebook fans, our articles have been read over 200,000 times and hundreds of thousands of you have watched our videos and memes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where we stand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/where-we-stand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 20:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/where-we-stand/</guid>
      <description>In modern-day Scotland, we see:&#xA;A country unnecessarily divided as Nationalist leaders promote division to boost their own power&amp;nbsp;Our friends and neighbours entranced by ugly Nationalism and influenced daily by dishonest propaganda churned out by the Nationalist establishmentPoliticians who always put their immature dreams above the welfare of the peopleA looming one-party state where unsuitable and incompetent people are promoted based on party loyaltyAn ineffective and divided oppositionLeaders who casually dismiss the vote of the majority And we see the silent majority of Scots cowed into silence and ignored by the government and the media.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
