<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economy &amp;Amp; Business on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/economy-amp-business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economy &amp;Amp; Business on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 21:44:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/economy-amp-business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When leaders lie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-leaders-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 21:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-leaders-lie/</guid>
      <description>It is often said in these post-truth times, that a lie has gone half-way around the world before the truth has put its boots on. Why do lies, fake news and misinformation gain so much more political traction than evidence-based facts? The answer to that question can be found in the world of tribal epistemology.&#xA;In 2017, David Roberts of Vox news coined the term ‘tribal epistemology’ to describe a state of mind ’where you believe not what facts or reason or top experts say is true, but what your group or tribe say is true, especially its leaders’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola&#39;s fake economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicolas-fake-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 17:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicolas-fake-economy/</guid>
      <description>The story goes that in 1787, as Russian Empress Catherine the Great travelled in the Crimea, her minister Grigory Potemkin erected fake portable villages along her route as a façade to hide deep-seated poverty in the region.&#xA;The Potemkin Villages, as they became known, were the means by which the gilded monarch was persuaded that all was right with the country under her gaze even though the truth was the opposite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing up for Scottish business</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/standing-up-for-scottish-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 20:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/standing-up-for-scottish-business/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IBstNm-ESs8&#xD;This article is an edited version of the above video, first broadcast on Monday, 19th October.&#xA;Having spent most of my life running my own businesses, in Japan, the United States and now in Scotland, it makes me really angry to see how the Scottish Government treats businesses here in Scotland.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;I remember starting my first business in Tokyo, making what became Japan’s number one English magazine. Like a lot of business owners, we used all our savings to get started.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Neverendum is killing Scottish jobs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-neverendum-is-killing-scottish-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 21:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-neverendum-is-killing-scottish-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Fiona Hyslop, Scottish Cabinet Secretary for Economy, Fair Work and Culture, was asked in Holyrood about when the 28,000 green jobs, that were promised by Alex Salmond in 2010, would be delivered. She answered, “When we have the powers of ‘independence’.”&amp;nbsp;&#xA;In other words, the SNP-controlled Scottish Government has been unable to create the jobs they promised, but, somehow, will be magically free to create them after Scotland separates from the rest of the UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five more ways Nicola Sturgeon has failed Scotland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-more-ways-nicola-sturgeon-has-failed-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-more-ways-nicola-sturgeon-has-failed-scotland/</guid>
      <description>The very first article on this site, Nicola Sturgeon’s five biggest failures, got a huge response, with over 14,400 views so far.&amp;nbsp; But, so many of you said ‘Only five..?’ And we agree, so here’s some more of our First Minister&#39;s failures. Share widely...&#xA;#5 Dude, where’s our superfast broadband?&#xD;Lockdown measures over the last few months have really shown the importance of a reliable and fast broadband connection. In their 2016 election manifesto, the SNP proclaimed they would ensure “100% of premises across Scotland will have access to super-fast broadband by 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunak skelps the Nationalists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sunak-skelps-the-nationalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 21:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sunak-skelps-the-nationalists/</guid>
      <description>Commentary by Tommi Kerr.&#xA;On Wednesday afternoon, the Chancellor of Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, delivered a typically impressive performance in the House of Commons. Outlining the next phase of governmental support for the British people, he spoke passionately about protecting livelihoods before announcing an imaginative set of measures intended to kick-start the UK economy.&#xA;The&amp;nbsp;speech&amp;nbsp;– entitled ‘A Plan for Jobs’ – contained several notable soundbites. The measures themselves were eye-catching, with a floundering hospitality sector receiving special attention in the form of a VAT reduction and a new policy dubbed ‘Eat Out to Help Out’ – cue much innuendo on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
