<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Scexit Files on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/the-scexit-files/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Scexit Files on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 20:21:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/the-scexit-files/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Disgusted of Prestonpans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/disgusted-of-prestonpans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 20:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/disgusted-of-prestonpans/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: The National, 27th April 2021&#xA;Letters to the Editor:&#xA;Sir – Enough is enough! We have ferries that don’t float, an education system that’s sinking and we’re still top of the Champions League for drug deaths and child poverty. And if that wasn’t enough, ministers in Holyrood are dishing out ‘pork pies’ while their friends have a hand in the till.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;So, why-oh-why hasn’t the SNP found a proper scapegoat for all these shenanigans?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Albania!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/welcome-to-albania/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 22:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/welcome-to-albania/</guid>
      <description>STV Online: 15th August 2029&#xA;Scotland is about to undergo the biggest rebranding since the abolition of Pictland in the 9th century, according to documents seen by STV.&#xA;The Alba-SNP government has refused to comment on leaks that the post-Scexit Rebranding and De-Britification Commission has recommended a change to the country’s name, aiming to reposition it within the global marketplace.&#xA;Rumours that Alba would be incorporated into the official nomenclature have been circulating for months since the SNP was relegated to junior partner in the ruling coalition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The People’s Front of Caledonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-peoples-front-of-caledonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 21:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-peoples-front-of-caledonia/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: The Spectator, 10th April 2021&#xA;At a tense briefing yesterday, SNP sources strenuously denied that any detergent was used to enforce ideological purity during the ongoing Sturgeonista-Salmondite split. The allegation emerged after a recording of a recent internal strategy meeting was obtained by The Spectator. An extract has now been published below in the public interest. (Identities have been amended for legal reasons).&amp;nbsp;&#xA;IAN: “TRAITORS!”&#xA;RUTH: “The Salmondite front is a total irrelevance now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scexit means Sex-it!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/scexit-means-sex-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 22:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/scexit-means-sex-it/</guid>
      <description>The Sunday Mail, 17 Apr. 2022&#xA;Indy supporters were whipped into a frenzy yesterday as S&amp;amp;M for Scotland officially launched under the eye-catching banner ‘PAIN IS GAIN.’&#xA;The group’s Master-dominator, Donny Frank, was unrepentant. “Indy is KINKY” he proclaimed to supporters at the Cockburn Centre in Edinburgh. The campaign draws on the Marquis de Sade’s principle that psychological satisfaction comes only through enduring and inflicting sustained bouts of carefully controlled agony.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Budget Shock for Rip Van McWinkle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/budget-shock-for-rip-van-mcwinkle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 14:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/budget-shock-for-rip-van-mcwinkle/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: Business Scotland, 10th March 2030&#xA;“Ffffwwhaa!!” the man spluttered, “£17.49 for a pint!” almost choking on his own tongue. “Are you oot o’ y’r mind?”&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The CCTV camera caught it all. Facial recognition soon identified him as a Mr Rip Van McWinkle, ‘innocently’ ordering a well-deserved drink at the Glen Laggard Inn.&#xA;“Scots pounds,” the landlady explained.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Rip was too busy grumbling to listen – “rassinfrassin-poundzapint” – as he fished through his coins one by methodical one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>At Home with the Macbeths</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/at-home-with-the-macbeths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 21:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/at-home-with-the-macbeths/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files:&amp;nbsp; Channel Four, 5 March 2021&#xA;This week, Celebrity Gogglebox is in Cawdor with retired assassins, Lord and Lady Macbeth, as they cosy up together on the sofa. They’ve just been watching the latest news report from their homeland on Scotland’s current power couple.&#xA;“What the ????☠⭍ !!!,” grunts Macbeth to his wife. “Don’t they ever learn?”&#xA;Her ladyship nods. “That fishy woman can’t even organise a couple of witches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Self-hating Scots’ urged to belt up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/self-hating-scots-urged-to-belt-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 21:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/self-hating-scots-urged-to-belt-up/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: Daily Record, 14th Sept. 2028&#xA;A festival of penny-pinching opened yesterday, as the newly appointed Finance Minister, Kylie Krankie, launched the inaugural Queen&#39;s Awards for Belt-tightening on behalf of the post-Scexit government.&#xA;“I’m just bursting to tell everyone!” exclaimed Valerie Spark, after scooping the energy award. The young entrepreneur has plans to re-configure running machines in gyms across the country to supply the Scottish National Grid. “It’s a great way to tap into our extensive resources of obesity, after North Sea oil starts running out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Strange Case of Dr Heckle and Indy Hyde</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-strange-case-of-dr-heckle-and-indy-hyde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 16:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-strange-case-of-dr-heckle-and-indy-hyde/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: Sunday Herald, 15th July 2026&#xA;“I lied in good faith.”&amp;nbsp;&#xA;With those words, Dr Jim Heckle, the Minister for Strategy in the post-Scexit cabinet, abruptly quit the Scottish government yesterday, citing mental health issues.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;“Since Indy, it’s been absolutely pile-driving,” Heckle explained in an exclusive interview with the Sunday Herald. “But the real problem with … y’know … cracking up,” he sobbed, “is that you don’t see it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Pied Bagpipers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-pied-bagpipers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 17:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-pied-bagpipers/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files : Scots Magazine, 7 Apr. 2026&#xA;“Eeek … eek …”&#xA;The rats – gazillions of them – rampaged through the town, devouring every scrap, morsel and crumb. Ever since the financial crisis, the townsfolk had been plagued with them. But “… whazzzat?” A volley of drums crackled as the skirl of chanters blasted up street and alley, louder ‘n’ LOUDER till the pipers were marching inside your head … or so it seemed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old MacDonald had a Scapegoat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/old-macdonald-had-a-scapegoat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 20:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/old-macdonald-had-a-scapegoat/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files : Farming Today, 17 July, 2027&#xA;Old Mac is proud of his scapegoats. “My herd can be blamed for pretty much everything – from wars to waiting lists. Anything that gets your goat, really.” The old breeder is especially fond of his ram. “He’s a pure Old English. In great demand, these days.”&#xA;Prices have duly soared since Scexit. “It has been great for business,” he chuckles. Ever since border checks were introduced, you can’t get UK scapegoats for love nor money.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ministers hail anti-Union vaccine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/ministers-hail-anti-union-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 17:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/ministers-hail-anti-union-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: The Herald, February 2028&#xA;Not since independence have ministers been so upbeat. The spike in second thoughts has continued to spread across Scotland, but finally the long-awaited Anti-Unionist vaccine (ANTI-U 27) has been given emergency approval by regulators. Officials welcomed the announcement. “As we have said repeatedly, the Scottish government has always followed the ideology,” a spokesperson insisted. “But now I am pleased to say we have five million doses of hope.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Scotsmas Carol</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-scotsmas-carol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 18:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-scotsmas-carol/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files : (Scottish Review of Books, 20th Dec. 2030)&#xA;“Bloody humbuggery!” muttered McScrooge as the lights flickered ominously. Rob McCratchit, his so-called ‘special advisor,’ had taken a day off and now – dammit – the Finance Minister had to write his own seasonal message.&#xA;‘Happy Scotsmas to one and all …’&#xA;Crivvens!! Stuck already. Where the hell was McCratchit when you really needed him? Sighing deeply, McScrooge rested his leaden head against the monitor until his thoughts drifted onto …</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The All-seeing Eye</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-all-seeing-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 20:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-all-seeing-eye/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: New Scientist, April 2025&#xA;“Nothing escapes The Eye,” grins Dr Dave Bowman.&#xA;His lab at Heriot Watt has just unveiled the latest big data computer project that will revolutionise political campaigning. With cutting edge artificial intelligence, The Eye aims to win – and win big.&#xA;“Remember how Dominic Cummings scribbled for hours to come up with ‘Take Back Control’,” Bowman says. “Now, The Eye can pump out a killer slogan in 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jolly Scottianity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/jolly-scottianity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 17:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/jolly-scottianity/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: The Tablet, 1 Dec. 2026&#xA;The Reverend I. M. Jolly is not his normal sunny self: “We’re doomed, I tell ye … doomed.”&#xA;The minister’s eyelids have been fluttering like moths since the Church of Scotland was stripped of its status as the official religion in Scexit Scotland. “And to think I supported Indy,” he groans.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;“The referendum asked ‘Do you believe&#39; …,” the wistful clergyman recalls. “So, of course, I answered YES,” he admits, “… at least on Sundays.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Scotland Independent Again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/make-scotland-independent-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 17:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/make-scotland-independent-again/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: BBC News Online 11 November 2021&#xA;Like a tank with a flamethrower, President Trump has set the heather ablaze from his golf buggy at Turnberry.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;With legal battles still ongoing to decide the winner of the 2020 election, The Donald startled photographers as he trundled down the fairway, wearing a blue baseball cap with the striking message: Make Scotland Independent Again.&#xA;Experts agree, not since De Gaulle ended a state visit to Canada with ‘Vive le Quebec libre&#39; has anyone let loose with such a rip-roaring, undiplomatic stinker.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hail to the Chief, Gorgeous George</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/hail-to-the-chief-gorgeous-george/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 18:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/hail-to-the-chief-gorgeous-george/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: (Hello Magazine, 16 Aug 2025)&#xA;As a gathering of the clans, it was a pretty rum affair. Two hundred and more Galloways stood on the slopes of The Merrick (2766 ft) to select their new chief after the ancient post lay vacant.&#xA;The vote, by acclamation, was unanimous. Swathed in plaid, the victor – known hereafter as The Galloway – beamed benevolently in his lizard-green regalia after officials at the Court of Lord Lyon, King at Arms, confirmed his appointment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cabertosser to the rescue!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/cabertosser-to-the-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 15:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/cabertosser-to-the-rescue/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: The Economist, 30 Nov 2025&#xA;It’s official: Dennis the Menace – and Gnasher – have been nationalised. In a milestone for Scotland’s post-Independence industrial policy, ministers raised a dram yesterday as DC Thomson was finally brought under public ownership.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The takeover was agreed after a Nationalist boycott of the traditionally Unionist company led directors to raise the white flag earlier in the year. “We used Bash Street Kids tactics against them … heh-heh-heh,” admitted a Culture Ministry official on condition of anonymity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mac Lives Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/mac-lives-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 15:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/mac-lives-matter/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: Sunday Post, 15 Aug. 2025&#xA;Chaos came to Princes Street yesterday after Mac Lives Matter campaigners targeted Edinburgh’s iconic Scott Monument. The 197 foot ‘gothic rocket’ survived the attempt to drill through its supporting pillars, but Sir Walter Scott’s head did not.&#xA;Police cordoned off the scene as engineers inspected the damage. The attack is the most daring act so far in the unofficial MLM campaign to cleanse Scotland’s capital of ‘colonial’ symbols ahead of the first anniversary of independence in December.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mummy Returns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-mummy-returns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 15:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-mummy-returns/</guid>
      <description>The Scexit Files: Sunday Post, 15th Nov 2024&#xA;Fury broke out last night in the deadlocked Scexit negotiations. With Scottish independence officially set for Hogmanay 2024, the ‘divorce settlement’ is reaching the end game. The latest row exploded when Scottish government sources insisted on a share of the British Museum’s Egyptian collection. Officials stressed they were simply adapting the Salmond principle: “After all, it’s Scotland’s loot too.”&#xA;Last month, the Post reported on the controversial deal to divide Lord Elgin’s historic bequests to the museum (see ‘Don’t Lose our Marbles,’ 25th Oct 2024).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
