<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Commentary on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/commentary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Commentary on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 17:25:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/commentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Independence Is Dead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/independence-is-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 17:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/independence-is-dead/</guid>
      <description>This week, John Swinney launched yet another desperate push to try to break up the UK, this time fronted by a glossy poster declaring:&#xA;“Scotland is a nation. We affirm that every nation has the right to choose its own future. We choose a future where Scotland decides its own government…This is our plea, our right, and our opportunity: To place who live here at the heart of our national opportunity: democracy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There is no ‘Union Dividend’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/there-is-no-union-dividend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 19:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/there-is-no-union-dividend/</guid>
      <description>+++&#xA;So called pro-UK politicians from both the Conservatives and Labour often trumpet the “Union dividend” — the extra billions Scotland receives from the United Kingdom — as proof that staying in the UK benefits ordinary Scots. On paper, the numbers seem impressive: according to the Government Expenditure and Revenue Scotland (GERS) 2024–25 report, Scotland receives £2,669 more per person in public spending than the UK average.&#xA;But in reality, this dividend is wasted as under the SNP, Scotland’s extra funding is being squandered on a bloated, inefficient, and politically motivated public sector, while schools, hospitals, and local services continue to decline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop lying: Demographics isn&#39;t Destiny</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-lying-demographics-isnt-destiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 01:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-lying-demographics-isnt-destiny/</guid>
      <description>+++&#xA;John Swinney, the current SNP leader, and his predecessor, Nicola Sturgeon, have recently resorted to a familiar tactic: invoking youth demographics to justify the party’s continued push for Scottish independence. Both have attempted to frame support among 16- to 24-year-olds as proof of an inevitable shift toward separation from the United Kingdom.&#xA;In a recent speech at the SNP’s conference, Swinney cited a poll commissioned by The National—the nationalists&#39; propaganda paper —which claimed 63% of 16- to 24-year-olds backed independence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pincer Movement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/pincer-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/pincer-movement/</guid>
      <description>The United Kingdom faces a persistent challenge from separatist movements, particularly in Scotland, where the Scottish National Party (SNP) has pursued independence with unrelenting focus. Despite the intentions behind devolution, the existence of devolved legislatures like Holyrood has amplified the separatist agenda rather than diminished it. To secure the UK, a pragmatic dual strategy—a short-term defense and a long-term solution—is required.&#xA;The Failure of Devolution to Quell Separatism When devolution was introduced, proponents like Labour politician George Robertson claimed it would &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop lying about GERS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-lying-about-gers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 18:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-lying-about-gers/</guid>
      <description>With the SNP’s conference now taking place, shortly after the annual Government Expenditure and Revenue Scotland Report (GERS) has just been published, now is an ideal time to stop nationalists&#39; lies and misdirections and their dismissals about the state of Scotland’s finances.&#xA;These dismissals follow the same forms:&#xA;GERS is produced by the UK Government to discredit Scotland GERS does not give a real picture of Scotland’s finances These are followed by two self-serving arguments:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are NOT ‘stuck with’ devolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-are-not-stuck-with-devolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 18:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-are-not-stuck-with-devolution/</guid>
      <description>Today marks the 25th anniversary of the first session of The Scottish Parliament. As expected, a host of insiders, including Scottish Labour politicians, are saying they are proud of what has been achieved, while Scots wonder if those politicians – who are almost all receiving a salary from the Scottish Parliament – have somehow missed the past 25 years.&#xA;https://twitter.com/AnasSarwar/status/1789621341777178825 So let’s cast our minds back to 1997 and ask the question that is not being asked: What if legislative devolution was not part of New Labour’s manifesto, and it never happened?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Losers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-biggest-losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 12:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-biggest-losers/</guid>
      <description>As we head towards a UK General Election, where a resurgent Labour is expected to form the next government by a wide margin, thoughts turn to those hapless SNP MPs who will likely lose their seats. As Warren Buffett said, &#39;Only when the tide goes out do you discover who&#39;s been swimming naked.&#39; And in the upcoming election, the electoral tide is going to go so far out against the SNP, it will leave the majority of its MPs metaphorically naked, out in the cold and wondering where their yellow swimsuits went.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Search of The Golden Grievance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/in-search-of-the-golden-grievance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 21:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/in-search-of-the-golden-grievance/</guid>
      <description>After 17 years of SNP rule, support for Scexit would appear to be finally on the decline. A recent opinion poll ranked Scexit as only the 7th (18%) most important topic that would decide voting intention at the next General Election. Way out in front was the economy on 64%. This must be gut-wrenching news for independence supporters: 17 years in power and zero progress made in convincing Scots to vote for Independence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SNP has never had a mandate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-never-had-a-mandate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 17:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-never-had-a-mandate/</guid>
      <description>It is a commonly touted assertion of the SNP that all elections, Westminster or devolved, will be referendums on independence and if they achieve a majority of some kind then this will give them a mandate for independence. But what does ‘mandate’ actually mean?&amp;nbsp;&#xA;A standard definition (via Google) of a mandate is:&#xA;The authority to carry out a policy, regarded as given by the electorate to a party or candidate that wins an election.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Lie That Won&#39;t Die</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-lie-that-wont-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 21:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-lie-that-wont-die/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, Reverend Stu Campbell of Bath, aka Wings Over Scotland, proudly revealed an anniversary. It was 12 years, he breathlessly announced in a post called The Longest Lie, since he first debunked the notion that Scottish votes influence the outcome of UK General Elections. The last time it happened was 1964, he told his adoring followers. Quite a statistic. But is it true?&#xA;Not even remotely. As in, not only is it misleading, it is demonstrably false.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reasons to be cheerful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/reasons-to-be-cheerful/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 22:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/reasons-to-be-cheerful/</guid>
      <description>It’s an often repeated theme of anti-UK nationalism (the SNP in Scotland especially) that there is a popular demand from the UK public to break up the UK. They bleat repeatedly in a monotone like sheep ‘The Union is dead’ in a sad attempt at creating the impression that the UK will inevitably break up. They have to maintain this fiction as any look at the objective, verifiable, empirical facts (data and statistical evidence) gives the conclusion that in ALL parts of the UK, a clear and often substantial majority of the public want to keep the UK together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Domino Effect</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-domino-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 18:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-domino-effect/</guid>
      <description>The Domino Effect was a dominant theory (mostly in the US) during the Cold War period – when anxiety about Communism’s real intentions in Europe and the wider world was at its height – that as one country became controlled by Communism, then inevitably, by a process of contamination, states bordering it would also fall under its domination, like toppling dominoes in a row. This theory was the basis of US and other countries’ foreign policy and helped fuel armed conflicts in the post-1945 period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sturgeon’s leadership failures brought to book</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-leadership-failures-brought-to-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 20:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-leadership-failures-brought-to-book/</guid>
      <description>In his new book on post-war European leaders, Tom Gallagher assesses Nicola Sturgeon&#39;s disastrous legacy, and how her failure provides an insight into Europe’s Leadership Famine.&#xA;Nicola Sturgeon definitely merits a chapter in a book on European leadership. It isn’t because she left Scotland a better place than she found it or because under her the independence cause flourished. Neither thing happened. Indeed, many of the 12,000 people who crowded into Scotland’s main events venue, the Hydro in Glasgow on 22 November 2014 to hail her emergence as First Minister of devolved Scotland and leader of the Scottish National Party (SNP) would today bitterly assail her as a fraud who had duped them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is written: Westminster is the UK’s sovereign parliament</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/it-is-written-westminster-is-the-uks-sovereign-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 19:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/it-is-written-westminster-is-the-uks-sovereign-parliament/</guid>
      <description>In the past week, the SNP has been trying to recapture the narrative, away from Sturgeon’s criminal investigation, to constitutional issues. Humza Yousaf has proposed that an independent Scotland adopts a ‘written constitution’:&#xA;Westminster has already been able to undermine the devolution settlement, override decisions made by an elected Scottish Parliament...In future, Westminster sovereignty could even allow the UK parliament to repeal devolution through nothing other than a simple majority vote.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federalism: The nationalist wolf in sheep&#39;s clothing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/federalism-the-nationalist-wolf-in-sheeps-clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 18:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/federalism-the-nationalist-wolf-in-sheeps-clothing/</guid>
      <description>It seems no matter what constitutional problems the UK has, someone will always propose federalism as a solution. But federalism isn&#39;t the benign cuddly sheep it first appears to be. It&#39;s the nationalist wolf in disguise, ready to divide and devour the UK. Federalism, like all attempts to appease nationalism, will only further aid the fragmentation of the constitutional cohesion of our country, and should be opposed by all those who want to maintain its integrity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reform or Abolish?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/reform-or-abolish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 17:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/reform-or-abolish/</guid>
      <description>The final part of The Majority&#39;s three-part series on the failure of Scottish Devolution and the options to reform or abolish the Scottish Parliament. Part 1 – How we got here&#xA;Part 2 – Power Grabs, Waste &amp;amp; Scandal The first part of this series covered how legislative devolution grew from a concept into the reality of the Scottish Assembly, and talked about how, rather than acting as a bulwark against nationalism, it has become a UK Government-funded vehicle for nationalism and constitutional division.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Power Grabs, Waste &amp; Scandal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/power-grabs-waste-scandal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 20:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/power-grabs-waste-scandal/</guid>
      <description>Part 2 of a three-part series on the failure of Scottish Devolution and the options to reform or abolish the Scottish Parliament. Part 1 – How did we got here?&#xA;Before a system can be fixed or abolished, we need a clear understanding of the problems and issues of the current system of Legislative Devolution:&#xA;Constitutional conflict Centralisation Excessive spending Lack of accountability Constitutional Power Grabs It is a well-known fact that political organisations always aim to expand their power.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scotland&#39;s devolution disaster</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/scotlands-devolution-disaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 14:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/scotlands-devolution-disaster/</guid>
      <description>It’s been 25 years since the devolution experiment was inflicted on Scotland, and the result is an unspeakable disaster. It’s a disaster because The Scottish Parliament, which was set up to stop Scottish Nationalism, is now being abused by the SNP to promote a separatist agenda, while Scotland’s services decline daily and scandal mounts up. And it is ‘unspeakable’ because few want to discuss whether the source problem is devolution itself, even its natural opponents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After the earthquake, a tsunami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/after-the-earthquake-a-tsunami/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/after-the-earthquake-a-tsunami/</guid>
      <description>It’s said that before a tsunami strikes there are major warning signs to look out for that should alert the public to the forthcoming catastrophe. Warning signs such as an earthquake at sea, or the tide suddenly going out, are usually enough to galvanise the inhabitants of neighbouring coastal towns to immediately head for the high ground.&#xA;Political tsunamis have striking similarities to the real thing. For example, there were many early warning signs before the 2015 General Election that alerted all pro-UK parties in Scotland to the very real possibility that they were going to be swept away by a gigantic nationalist tidal wave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Love Story, Baby just say Yes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/its-a-love-story-baby-just-say-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 22:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/its-a-love-story-baby-just-say-yes/</guid>
      <description>I asked Chat-GPT to write an article based on a series of tweets I&#39;d written about Wings Over Scotland&#39;s UDI plan. And for good measure, I asked it to weave in the titles of Taylor Swift songs. Why not?&#xA;---&#xA;Wings Over Scotland recently revealed a plan for a unilateral declaration of independence (UDI), which has been taken on wholeheartedly by Ash Regan, that can only be described as a fairytale, swirling with magical thinking and a total detachment from reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Bridge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-golden-bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 21:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-golden-bridge/</guid>
      <description>This is a topic that many of you don&#39;t want to hear. But, as committed as we are to destroying nationalist delusions, we must also assess anti-nationalist delusions as well, of which the main one is that the only strategy to beat the SNP is a Labour-Tory alliance.&#xA;Not only is an alliance not going to happen, Labour’s strategy of not forming an alliance with the Scottish Tories is correct. This also means that recent attacks on Tories by Labour are also correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The kids are not alright</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-kids-are-not-alright/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 18:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-kids-are-not-alright/</guid>
      <description>So the SNP is&amp;nbsp;intending&amp;nbsp;to “extend the right to stand for election to sixteen year olds.” Who knew? I had assumed that&amp;nbsp;they&amp;nbsp;already&amp;nbsp;were&amp;nbsp;but maybe Ross Greer, the wokier-than-thou Scottish Green MSP only&amp;nbsp;identifies&amp;nbsp;as sixteen. It is, I am forced to admit, a brilliant strategy. At a stroke ‘gammons’ and ‘boomers’ like me will be focused on this latest provocation rather than asking how the Scottish ‘government’ could possibly have&amp;nbsp;committed around £240,000,000 &amp;nbsp;in the shipyards and still have no ferries; or where the allegedly missing £660,000 from the SNP’s ‘indy fund’ is; or how it is that Nicola Sturgeon’s publisher allegedly received over £295,000 of public money prior to the publication of her ‘inspirational’ selected speeches&amp;nbsp;Women Hold up Half the Sky&amp;nbsp;(a title borrowed from Chairman Mao); or what has happened to the&amp;nbsp;£5bn&amp;nbsp;Covid support money destined for Scottish businesses&amp;nbsp;that Audit Scotland think is unaccounted for?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SNP’s dangerous referendum fantasies must be stopped</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snps-dangerous-referendum-fantasies-must-be-stopped/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 10:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snps-dangerous-referendum-fantasies-must-be-stopped/</guid>
      <description>Normally, I wouldn’t write a whole article on some internet rando, but in a video posted on March 3, Gordon Ross, a driving instructor from Partick, who styles himself with the bad pun ‘Inde-car guy’ (on Twitter as @PartickDriver), claimed that he has been given the answers to how the SNP will conduct its second referendum campaign, directly from Mike Russell, the party’s President and former ‘Cabinet Secretary for the Constitution, Europe and External Affairs’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking up the UK is not a ‘respectable cause’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/breaking-up-the-uk-is-not-a-respectable-cause/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 20:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/breaking-up-the-uk-is-not-a-respectable-cause/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I haven’t been able to work on as many articles as I’d like. Setting up and running our podcast was a lot of work. Now that’s more settled, I hope to get more articles out regularly. Thank you for your patience.&#xA;—&#xA;The SNP pensions brouhaha rumbles on, with the reality-based community trying vainly to impress upon delusional nationalists that they are living in a fantasy world. A ‘fact check’ in The National newspaper presented two options: the UK will continue to pay Scots pensions because 1) the UK currently pays the pensions of UK citizens who live overseas 2) If you claim dual citizenship i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scotland&#39;s lost socialists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/scotlands-lost-socialists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 19:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/scotlands-lost-socialists/</guid>
      <description>This is a story of three artists, all leaders in their fields: an actor, a musician and an author. They are known, not just for their world-leading skills, but for their authenticity. These working-class men have developed and promoted their talents to the top of their fields and have gained as much respect from the quality of their work as from their uncompromising attitude to their craft. No-one can say that their work, and attitude to it, is not authentic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wings Over Scotland RIP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/wings-over-scotland-rip/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 16:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/wings-over-scotland-rip/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Reverend Stuart Campbell, the blogger known as Wings Over Scotland, declared, in a 4300-word suicide note, that his blogging days are over. Campbell had previously said that he had retired, but this apparently, is the ‘last, last’ time.&#xA;To signify the end of the independence movement, Campbell used a somewhat laboured metaphor of the Rolling Stones concert at Altamont in December 1969, which, due to a murder of an audience member by Hell&#39;s Angels, signalled the end of the swinging 60s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake tweets, dubious hires and anti-English hate: There&#39;s a cancer at Newsquest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/fake-tweets-dubious-hires-and-anti-english-hate-theres-a-cancer-at-newsquest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 11:07:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/fake-tweets-dubious-hires-and-anti-english-hate-theres-a-cancer-at-newsquest/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, the Independent Press Standards Organisation (IPSO) upheld a complaint brought by Mr Neil Lovatt against The National newspaper. IPSO concluded that The National newspaper fabricated tweets and breached the Editors&#39; Code in a video and article it published in April. The Majority was made aware of this case a few weeks ago, but was not able to publish until it had been appealed and concluded.&#xA;The ruling is part of a pattern of hideous behaviour at Newsquest, The National’s publisher, which not only publishes anti-English hate; it has provided platforms for two of Scotland’s most odious commentators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When leaders lie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-leaders-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 21:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-leaders-lie/</guid>
      <description>It is often said in these post-truth times, that a lie has gone half-way around the world before the truth has put its boots on. Why do lies, fake news and misinformation gain so much more political traction than evidence-based facts? The answer to that question can be found in the world of tribal epistemology.&#xA;In 2017, David Roberts of Vox news coined the term ‘tribal epistemology’ to describe a state of mind ’where you believe not what facts or reason or top experts say is true, but what your group or tribe say is true, especially its leaders’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop the Neverendum: Ban secession now.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-the-neverendum-ban-secession-now./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 15:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/stop-the-neverendum-ban-secession-now./</guid>
      <description>The UK Government should stop gambling with its territorial, economic, cultural and social integrity.&#xA;A couple of weeks ago, Alister Jack, the Secretary of State for Scotland, said that Scots could have a second ‘independence’ referendum if polls showed a consistent majority of 60% of Scots in favour of it. Gambling your country&#39;s future on the basis of opinion polls is certainly an interesting strategy, but, as I was getting ready to publish this article, the UK Government finally pushed back on Jack’s comments, saying, ‘We’ve never set a position on that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where’s my apology, Janey?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/wheres-my-apology-janey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/wheres-my-apology-janey/</guid>
      <description>A response to online bullying, based on false accusations of harassment, made against me by LEN PENNIE and JANEY GODLEY&#xA;It’s not easy to publicly admit that you’ve been bullied, but a stand has to be made.&#xA;On August 24, Len Pennie, a 21-year-old woman who posts poetry and &#39;Scots Word of The Day’ videos on social media, under the name Miss PunniePennie (@lenniesaurus), made a false allegation that I harassed her, while claiming I am ‘creepy’ and ‘hateful’.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flogging a dead horse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/flogging-a-dead-horse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 22:54:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/flogging-a-dead-horse/</guid>
      <description>We live in a world saturated with media. It allows us to be ever more informed about the world around us, which is undeniably a good thing; but the media is a voracious beast that must be filled with constant opinion pieces, rehashed endlessly with never-ending arguments.&#xA;This is undoubtedly the case in Scotland, where the Separation question is perpetually discussed in articles which have become repetitive in the extreme and serve little more than justifying the wage of the writer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep dark secrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/deep-dark-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 17:52:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/deep-dark-secrets/</guid>
      <description>To those with even the most superficial understanding of Scottish politics, secrecy and cover-ups have become routine and embedded within the institutions of government and society. Within the past couple of weeks, we learned that the primary responsibility of Public Health Scotland is not, as some may have assumed, the public health of Scotland but rather the protection of SNP ministers. Furthermore, we learned that highly-touted “world-leading” policies on education, climate policy, transport and a myriad of other departments all fail, with no oversight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>87 years of failure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/87-years-of-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 21:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/87-years-of-failure/</guid>
      <description>Since the founding of the SNP 87 years ago, in 1934, they have had the ambition of breaking Scotland away from the rest of the UK, even during the darkest days of the Second World War. That seems hard to believe, given that Nicola Sturgeon admitted, less than two weeks ago, that she and the SNP still have no plan for the economic consequences of what would happen after a successful vote for separation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The irony of Scottish &#39;independence&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-irony-of-scottish-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 15:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-irony-of-scottish-independence/</guid>
      <description>Across the street from the Scottish Parliament, on Calton Hill, is buried one of the greatest Brits who ever lived. David Hume was a pioneer of the Scottish Enlightenment – a philosophical movement which helped lay the foundations of classical liberalism, a way of thinking about society that would come to define the modern world.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Hume was born when the United Kingdom was in its infancy, just four years after the 1707 Acts of Union which brought Scotland and England under the governance of one parliament.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tis but a scratch!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/tis-but-a-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 17:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/tis-but-a-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Last Thursday, working-class voters in England gave a resounding vote of confidence in Boris Johnson and an incumbent Tory government. Just a few miles north, though, here in Scotland, the Scottish Tories barely managed to hold on to their seat total.&#xA;The Scottish Conservatives are valiantly trying to portray this as a win, but they’re like the Black Knight in Monty Python and the Holy Grail, on the ground with their legs and arms cut off, saying ‘tis but a scratch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An empty vessel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-empty-vessel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 17:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-empty-vessel/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s over, finally. After a few nail-biting days, we know our election results; the SNP has gained a seat, a single extra seat snuck in on the lists. It was stressful. I spent the two days glued to my computer, sweating and fretting for the future of our country. I groaned with pain at the loss of East Lothian and Ayr; I yelled with relief at Dumbarton so loud my wife thought I was dying, and I breathed a sigh of relief at Aberdeenshire West.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boot this Homer Simpson parliament</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/boot-this-homer-simpson-parliament/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 01:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/boot-this-homer-simpson-parliament/</guid>
      <description>Holyrood is not a functioning parliament. In its place are 129 Homer Simpsons clinging to a donut. What Scotland needs more than anything, from COVID19 to unfinished hospitals to rusting ferries to fiscal blackholes is a turnaround team. My background is in medicine and surgery but also in health economics and management. One of the biggest challenges for health managers is turning around a failing hospital, or several hospitals, or even a whole organisation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cameron&#39;s folly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/camerons-folly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 20:37:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/camerons-folly/</guid>
      <description>Hindsight is a wonderful thing, if at times a depressing one. It enables me to see now that one man has been responsible for the dire state that Scotland is in. His name is David Cameron. As British Prime Minister, he played a strong hand as if he were on the defensive, and has consigned us to Neverendumland. He did much the same over Brexit, but that’s another story.&#xA;Cameron took the SNP’s electoral win in 2011 at face value and did not consider its detail and ramifications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about George</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/lets-talk-about-george/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/lets-talk-about-george/</guid>
      <description>As the election enters its final week, All For Unity has come under sustained attack from people on Twitter, led by Tory party activists, who, scared of losing list seats, have briefed candidates to launch personal attacks on George Galloway.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;To be honest, I was initially sceptical about George too. However, I had been awestruck by his debating skills in the US Senate, his passion in 2014 on the pro-UK side, and his commitment now to strategies that could beat the SNP and beat back the ugly and tiresome Nationalism that has brought Scotland to its knees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The magic is gone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-magic-is-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-magic-is-gone/</guid>
      <description>It has not been a good election campaign for Nicola Sturgeon and the SNP. Whilst the Conservatives continue to have a robust and loyal following, and Labour is increasing their vote share, with an energetic leader who, perhaps, became the first politician in history to dance in the street and not make a fool of himself.&#xA;The SNP magic is gone. Dogged by damaging scandals and bitter feuds over the last six months, the party desperately needed a charismatic and energetic campaign, something they currently seem incapable of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On yer bike</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/on-yer-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/on-yer-bike/</guid>
      <description>With a grand fanfare, the SNP released their manifesto. Never have I seen such desperation and cynical attempt to pass off a promise that &#34;we will try to fix what we broke&#34; as something new and revolutionary, done in such a fundamentally self-contradictory manner.&#xA;No doubt you will have heard the headline that the SNP will now give you a free bike. Well, one kid somewhere may end up getting their photo taken with a bike.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fragile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/fragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 18:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/fragile/</guid>
      <description>Famed polling guru, John Curtice, tells us Scotland is &#34;split down the middle&#34; on the constitutional question. When the undecideds are excluded, the polling for either side is within the margin of error of each other (about 3% in a poll of 1000 people). This is essentially where we were right before the vote in 2014, when the vast majority of undecided voters voted to remain part of the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What about Labour?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-about-labour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 21:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-about-labour/</guid>
      <description>Solidarity, collective resources, having more in common than differences, and working together in a shared identity and future. This is the basis of my political beliefs and my commitment to Unionism and the British family of nations and people.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;They are powerful arguments that we, a country welded together through shared pain and happiness, are &#34;better together&#34;. That we are even bigger, even stronger and even smarter than we could ever be apart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A lose-lose proposition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-lose-lose-proposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 22:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-lose-lose-proposition/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, following the widely covered announcement of Alex Salmond&#39;s new Alba party, those who listened very closely would have heard two distinct sounds: a pained groan and a jubilant celebration. For the SNP, it was a knife thrust deep into their back, and for Unionists, it was the joy of watching an enemy devour itself. Alba&#39;s hype — that it will somehow game the system and end up with an unchallengeable majority — is the ravings of a vindictive and ego-driven man high on his own supply.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don’t Like Mondays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/i-dont-like-mondays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 20:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/i-dont-like-mondays/</guid>
      <description>Like Bob Geldof and the Boomtown Rats, I don’t like Mondays, but today has been more depressing than usual. The first setback was hearing the BBC describe Nicola Sturgeon being cleared by an ‘independent’ inquiry. The second was reading an op-ed in The Times by Alex Massie, the Spectator’s Scottish editor, describing the SNP as “exhausted but irreplaceable.”&#xA;The riposte to the first has to be that if this was an inquiry into Donald Trump or Vladimir Putin, or almost anyone else, the BBC would not use the word ‘independent’ about an inquiry by an inquisitor carefully selected by the accused and limited by very delicately confined terms of reference before delivering a report that is at odds even with the leaked conclusions of the Kafkaesque Parliamentary Inquiry, which is then so heavily redacted as to be meaningless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shoot yourself in the foot. Repeat.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/shoot-yourself-in-the-foot.-repeat./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 22:51:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/shoot-yourself-in-the-foot.-repeat./</guid>
      <description>As a young man, I was given the kind of advice you never forget, but hope you will never have to prove right. I was driving with a colleague, through a volatile part of the world, on a research trip, where landmines are very common. As we got into the truck, he turned to me and said, &#34;Keep your feet as far apart as possible.&#34; I asked why and he replied, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Losing the narrative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/losing-the-narrative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 21:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/losing-the-narrative/</guid>
      <description>Controlling the narrative is vital to any information, or disinformation, campaign in politics and in policy. To achieve this, a political party will use several different tactics, such as catchy slogans, announcements, cover-ups and more. All these tactics fundamentally rely on someone to convey them from the party to the public: journalists and influencers that dominate the media and the online world.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The SNP have been able to control the narrative well, hiding their overtly divisive nationalism and objectively terrible record in government, which has allowed them to convince, or at least dissuade, criticism from most casual readers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A matter of gravity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-matter-of-gravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 22:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-matter-of-gravity/</guid>
      <description>Time is a unique concept; it is a variable constant that has come to dominate everyone&#39;s lives on this planet. Be it by the sun&#39;s movement and the need to care for cattle or the morning commute to your 9-5 job, time impacts us all, but we experience it in different ways.&#xA;One concept is that of time dilation, where the passage of time is different in two bodies depending on the velocity at which they travel; think of the masterful movie&amp;nbsp;Interstellar, where the protagonist in space experiences time much slower than his daughter on earth so that when they meet again, he seems not to have aged at all while his daughter is on her death bed from old age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clipped Wings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/clipped-wings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 22:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/clipped-wings/</guid>
      <description>Comedy is at its best when it reflects tragic reality. In the tragedy of Scottish politics, the comedy is becoming absurd. The SNP, mired in a civil war that is very much the Judean People&#39;s Front against the People&#39;s Front of Judea, are now seeing the arrival of the Judean People&#39;s Front crack suicide squad, as always confident that &#34;that will show &#39;em&#34;.&#xA;For years the SNP have shared, encouraged and supported Wings Over Scotland, a Nationalist website run by Reverend Stu Campbell (residence Bath, England).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Useful Idiots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/useful-idiots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 22:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/useful-idiots/</guid>
      <description>In politics, the end always justifies the means. People are nothing but tools to advance causes and ideologies. Due to this inevitable fact, political history is littered with &#34;useful idiots&#34;, people who champion and support a cause without knowing the full story behind it.&#xA;Scottish politics is no exception, and has more useful idiots than many other places. The EU used the SNP during the Brexit negotiations to leverage the British government.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ulsterisation of Scotland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-ulsterisation-of-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 21:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-ulsterisation-of-scotland/</guid>
      <description>I have spent most of my life as a soldier. I served six tours of duty in Northern Ireland between 1975 and 1995 before retiring as Regimental Sergeant Major in the Black Watch. I have seen a country tear itself apart before and I fear that we, as all who fail to learn from history, may find ourselves repeating it. I know that nowadays marches and large public gatherings seem like a distant memory, but those days will come back and with it, possibly, may come the start of our repeated history.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The war on your thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-war-on-your-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 20:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-war-on-your-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>The SNP’s obsession with being perceived as morally superior is the glue they collectively sniff before composing any public messaging. No matter the issue, rest assured that it cannot possibly be the SNP’s fault. Gone are the days of accountability, gone are the days of owning up to something and the days of transparency are but a faint memory.&#xA;Following the resounding ‘once in a generation’ 2014 referendum defeat, what did the SNP do?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola&#39;s fake economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicolas-fake-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 17:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicolas-fake-economy/</guid>
      <description>The story goes that in 1787, as Russian Empress Catherine the Great travelled in the Crimea, her minister Grigory Potemkin erected fake portable villages along her route as a façade to hide deep-seated poverty in the region.&#xA;The Potemkin Villages, as they became known, were the means by which the gilded monarch was persuaded that all was right with the country under her gaze even though the truth was the opposite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pull up. Pull up.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/pull-up.-pull-up./</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/pull-up.-pull-up./</guid>
      <description>Like many of us who now find ourselves locked inside for most of the day, I have been watching more movies than usual. A few nights ago, one struck me with its resonance to current Scottish politics. It was about an aircraft that, mid-flight, suffered a catastrophic malfunction to its tail assembly, causing it to roll over and enter a steep dive that inverted all of its controls; actions that would have previously lifted the nose of the aircraft would only push it down further.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SNP has no respect for democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-no-respect-for-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 18:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-no-respect-for-democracy/</guid>
      <description>There is a parallel universe where the SNP respects democracy.&#xA;In this alternative world in 2014, post referendum, Alex Salmond and Nicola Sturgeon acknowledged that two million people in Scotland had voted for Scotland to remain part of the United Kingdom and that the 10% winning margin —&amp;nbsp; which meant 24% more people voted NO than YES — was clear and decisive.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;To show their acceptance and heal the wounds of the divisive, “once-in-a-generation” referendum, three days after the referendum, they attended the service of reconciliation which the Church of Scotland had organised at St Giles Cathedral.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oh, Canada!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/oh-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/oh-canada/</guid>
      <description>Nationalists, the world over, love to think of themselves and their causes as unique, special and a product of their own &#34;glorious&#34; history. Still, as always, reality is far from their fevered imaginations.&#xA;For example, Separatist claims that &#34;independence is normal&#34; are easily dismissed by pointing out that many of the countries they claim to admire are, in fact, political unions, often far more recent than the UK.&#xA;As time goes on, and their desperate cries for secession are revealed as a gargantuan political squirrel, I am reminded more and more of other Separatist movements that have done exactly what the SNP have done and got just about as far as the SNP will.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dishonesty of Nationalist memes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-dishonesty-of-nationalist-memes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 17:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-dishonesty-of-nationalist-memes/</guid>
      <description>It seems that there are no depths to which the SNP and other separatist propaganda groups will not sink. Lies and chicanery are their customary modus operandi. One of the most recent comes from Chris Law, an SNP MP for Dundee, who has tweeted: ‘The Barnett Formula Myth Destroyed – it does not subsidise Scotland’.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;https://twitter.com/ChrisLawSNP/status/1347319507803648001 He bases this on a blog post by Gordon Macintyre-Kemp, leader of ‘Business for Scotland’, the sham business organisation which is nothing more than an SNP propaganda front.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twilight of the idols</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/twilight-of-the-idols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 19:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/twilight-of-the-idols/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember, just a few months ago, when statues were being toppled around the world? Men who had been venerated in their time were now exposed as having profited from slavery or other ignominious acts. What was surprising was how quickly it all happened. One day nobody cared; the next statues were being pulled down. How quickly times change.&#xA;The esteemed German sociologist Max Weber says leaders, in the past or today, derive their authority from three different sources: legal authority, traditional authority, and charismatic authority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illegal Referendums &#39;R&#39; Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/illegal-referendums-r-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 12:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/illegal-referendums-r-us/</guid>
      <description>In a major WORLD exclusive, The Majority has managed to get hold of Mike Russell&#39;s first draft of his 11-point plan for a referendum. See his orginal 12 points here, before they were massaged, soothed and tickled by an army of spin doctors...&#xA;The SNP&#39;s 12-point plan for an illegal referendum 1. We intend to fool our followers by proposing that we can hold a referendum on Scottish Separation.&#xA;2. A bonus is that we can distract them from Sturgeon’s problems in the Salmond inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s annoy the English!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/lets-annoy-the-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 21:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/lets-annoy-the-english/</guid>
      <description>In a recent conversation with a dear friend of mine, politics came up. I have known this man most of my life. We have similar political perspectives. We are employed in very similar fields; in fact, this man is almost identical to me, as many have noted, except he is English and I, Scottish.&#xA;As we discussed the state of the nation, he turned to me, and with a sigh, said: &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A wounded and desperate party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-wounded-and-desperate-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 22:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-wounded-and-desperate-party/</guid>
      <description>A curious paradox is occurring within the SNP and the broader Separation movement. The more secession becomes impractical, and even prohibitively so, the more they are determined to talk about it.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The SNP have failed to stop Brexit. Their alternative offers even more disruption. Their vaccination policy is lagging behind other parts of the UK, even though they claim the opposite. The COVID payouts they are responsible for have failed to materialise; the E.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/when/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 21:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/when/</guid>
      <description>When? It’s the perpetual separatist question. A question that seeps from every utterance. When will our ‘independence’ come? When will we be ‘free’? When will we get a second referendum?&#xA;I was asked recently, when I believe it is the right time to hold a second referendum and I gave it some thought. I said that I didn’t believe it should be this year or, for that matter, this decade. Perhaps after then?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The tide has turned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-tide-has-turned/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 20:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-tide-has-turned/</guid>
      <description>Since the 2016 Brexit referendum, uncertainty and pessimism have been the SNP&#39;s strongest allies, allowing them to recover their electoral losses and encouraging them to stir up evermore grievance for their own advantage.&#xA;If they were really committed to European ideals and the common market, they would have supported Theresa May&#39;s failed deal. However, they thrive on uncertainty. They were willing to sacrifice the stability, prosperity and social well-being of Scotland, and the UK, in pursuit of that uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Russia, with love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/from-russia-with-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 18:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/from-russia-with-love/</guid>
      <description>For those who, unfortunately, spend their time trawling through the endless toxic abuse and conspiracy theories that make up secessionist Twitter, you may have, aside from the usual whataboutery and false comparisons, noticed a common retort to questions on how exactly a separated Scotland would establish its organs of state. Many of these supposed “examples” reference the nations which were established after the collapse of the USSR between 1989 and 1992.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Separation is so great, why must you lie about it?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/if-separation-is-so-great-why-must-you-lie-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/if-separation-is-so-great-why-must-you-lie-about-it/</guid>
      <description>I have met a few Scottish nationalists, certainly a minority, who acknowledge the upheaval, to put it lightly, that the first decades of Separation would inevitably bring. They acknowledge the financial, social and political risks, the defence issues, the global and local problems - and to them, it is still worth it.&#xA;They are willing to undergo all that may happen because they fundamentally believe their sacrifice is required for Scotland to break away from the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vote SNP or else</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/vote-snp-or-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 22:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/vote-snp-or-else/</guid>
      <description>In my last commentary for The Majority, I spoke about how the SNP, and Nicola Sturgeon, in particular, treat us — the Scottish electorate — as nothing more than stepping stones towards the realisation of their immature, teenage dreams. There is nothing, and no one, they would not sacrifice, take advantage of, exploit or attack in this all-encompassing obsession. An obsession that has divided our country, communities and families for the last decade.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sturgeon’s stepping stones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-stepping-stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 18:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sturgeons-stepping-stones/</guid>
      <description>It seems to me that there is a gap between presentation - very, very good presentation - and the reality. When it comes to Coronavirus data, when it comes to education, when it comes to the Alex Salmond issue. There is a gap between how you present yourself - very, very effectively - and what’s really been going on in Scotland.&#xA;Andrew Marr, questioning Nicola Sturgeon - 29th November, 2020 https://twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untrue faith</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/untrue-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 22:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/untrue-faith/</guid>
      <description>Karl Marx famously stated that &#34;religion is the opiate of the people&#34;, claiming that the ruling elite used religion to subdue the proletariat into accepting their place in society, in the mines and in the factories, by convincing them that God had ordained their lot in life.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;If they did not upset the social order, they, the meek, would inherit the Earth in the afterlife. If they resisted, they would be punished with eternal damnation for questioning the will of God.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who wants Devolution?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/who-wants-devolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 19:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/who-wants-devolution/</guid>
      <description>Whether you like, or even agree with, Boris Johnson or not, he has done us all a huge favour by igniting a discussion on whether Devolution is a &#39;disaster&#39; or not.&#xA;In its 20th year, we are now in the ridiculous situation where the SNP, a party that never supported Devolution and wants to destroy it as soon as it can, is saying they support Devolution (they don’t), while Scottish Tories, who also never wanted Devolution, and who are appalled at the SNP takeover of the institution, are also saying they support it (they don’t).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scottish Empire, an inconvenient truth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-scottish-empire-an-inconvenient-truth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 17:41:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-scottish-empire-an-inconvenient-truth/</guid>
      <description>A Scotsman, an Englishman, a Welshman and an Irishman walked into a country, and they all took it.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;At 18.15 HKT on the 30th of June 1997, the &#34;sunset&#34; handover ceremony for the territory of Hong Kong took place on the&amp;nbsp;waterfront. To the cheers of the watching crowd, the Black Watch marched onto the parade square for the final time, in an event that, for many, symbolically marked the formal end of the British Empire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Will Remember Them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-will-remember-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 12:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/we-will-remember-them/</guid>
      <description>This morning, Sunday 8th Nov, at approximately 1045hrs, I took the final steps to the Black Watch Monument that overlooks the Fintry area of Dundee. This act of remembrance to the fallen, has become a regular feature in my life for many years – missed only when I have been working overseas.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Under the grey skies, I paid my respects with other service veterans, while socially distancing. We refrained from shaking hands and hugging, but we Will Remember Them in the time-honoured fashion, regardless of the Scottish Government ban on gatherings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bienvenido a la Unión</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/bienvenido-a-la-uni%C3%B3n/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 18:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/bienvenido-a-la-uni%C3%B3n/</guid>
      <description>Nationalists love to tell us that ‘independence is normal’. They will use false equivalences, manufacture grievances and exaggerate the most minute things, including chocolate bars, all in an attempt to further their narrative that they are singularly oppressed and that the cure for all lies in independence, even if that “cure” leads to even greater suffering.&#xA;They point to other countries, demanding to be like them, “independent”, without the slightest realisation of the errors or ironies of the comparison.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Silent Majority</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-silent-majority/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 12:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-silent-majority/</guid>
      <description>Once thing is certain: the polls were wrong, again. There was no Blue Wave. There was no Biden landslide. Despite being a &#39;racist&#39;, Trump increased his vote among Latinos and Blacks.&#xA;One would think that the media would know better by now. In 2016, The New York Times&#39; favourite pollster, Nate Silver, famously predicted that there was only an 8% chance of Trump winning. It was in the bag for Clinton.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citizens&#39; Theatre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/citizens-theatre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 19:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/citizens-theatre/</guid>
      <description>Who remembers all the fanfare and controversy surrounding the Scottish Government Citizens&#39; Assembly last year? Joanna Cherry and Lesley Riddoch bigging it up and Labour ex-MEP David Martin heading it up, then giving it up (he resigned for “personal” reasons). Less and less about it in the papers till a little noticed announcement two weeks ago saying it would finalise its vision on 10th October. So what does £1.5m get you?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Standing up for Scottish business</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/standing-up-for-scottish-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 20:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/standing-up-for-scottish-business/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IBstNm-ESs8 This article is an edited version of the above video, first broadcast on Monday, 19th October.&#xA;Having spent most of my life running my own businesses, in Japan, the United States and now in Scotland, it makes me really angry to see how the Scottish Government treats businesses here in Scotland.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;I remember starting my first business in Tokyo, making what became Japan’s number one English magazine. Like a lot of business owners, we used all our savings to get started.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bigger. Richer. Smarter.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/bigger.-richer.-smarter./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 10:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/bigger.-richer.-smarter./</guid>
      <description>We are not now that strength which in old days&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Moved earth and heaven, that which we are, we are;&amp;nbsp;&#xA;One equal temper of heroic hearts,&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Made weak by time and fate, but strong in will&amp;nbsp;&#xA;To strive, to seek, to find, and not to yield.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Alfred Tennyson, 1833&amp;nbsp;&#xA;In his description of the social paradoxes of late Soviet social life, the anthropologist&amp;nbsp; Alexi Yurchak expounds on the concept of &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control Freakery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/control-freakery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 12:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/control-freakery/</guid>
      <description>Last night, I published a video I had been forwarded of a group chat in which Nicola Sturgeon’s sister says that although Nicola is very tired she won’t delegate to her deputy because she is a ‘total control freak’.&#xA;https://twitter.com/themajorityscot/status/1318293732597399559 Personally, I think she needs a day or two off, and hand it over to her Deputy. But that&#39;s not Nicola, she&#39;s a total control freak. She wouldn&#39;t do that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Are we the baddies?’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/are-we-the-baddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 19:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/are-we-the-baddies/</guid>
      <description>Most of us have seen the Mitchell and Webb sketch, where a Nazi officer, worried about the skulls on his cap, ends up asking his fellow Nazi officer:&#xA;Are we the baddies?&#xA;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hn1VxaMEjRU The sketch strikes home because everyone thinks they are a good person, doing good things for good reasons. But sometimes even good people can find themselves doing bad things for bad reasons. Sometimes they can even be its cheerleaders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Act of Clarity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-act-of-clarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 14:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/an-act-of-clarity/</guid>
      <description>In an article in The Critic, Alliance for Unity’s Deputy Leader, Jamie Blackett, outlines eight ways which a UK Secession Clarity Act could clarify requirements before any secession referendum takes place. With many years before the next &#39;once-in-a-generation&#39; vote, Blackett argues that it makes sense to work out the rules in advance.&#xA;These rules would apply to any Scottish, Welsh or Northern Irish referenda and should be seen, not as roadblocks, but as paths to legitimacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The moral low ground</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-moral-low-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 19:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-moral-low-ground/</guid>
      <description>Time was when people could disagree about politics and remain civil. Taking a different view was a matter of opinion, not of moral superiority. Certainly, there were some politicians who cast moral aspersions (in Scotland, Labour against Tories), but public personal insults were not the norm. The referendum of 2014 changed all that.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The tone was set by Nicola Sturgeon, whose idea of debate was to shout down opponents such as Johann Lamont and Alistair Carmichael.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vote Indy, Get Tory</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/vote-indy-get-tory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 21:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/vote-indy-get-tory/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, a little-noticed poll by Wings over Scotland caught my attention. The headline result of the poll was that there was a 50-50 split in support for the question ‘Should Scotland be an independent country’. In fact, the results were:&#xA;Yes: 46%&amp;nbsp; No: 46%&amp;nbsp; Don’t Know 8%&#xA;While I’m sure many of you will take issue with the question wording, the fun starts when the following question is asked:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nordic dreams on the road to Belarus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nordic-dreams-on-the-road-to-belarus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 21:35:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nordic-dreams-on-the-road-to-belarus/</guid>
      <description>Nationalists love to point to Scandinavia as their vision of sunny, snow-capped uplands, and of joining their dream team of small economies as part of a ‘Northern Arc of Prosperity,’ as Salmond used to call it.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;However, we are never told how the journey will happen. Everything is sunny. There’s never any possibility of long detours, dangerous events, and dreich weather. Comparing Scotland to Nordic countries is simply a cheap trick that deflects from the reality of where we are now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The lies that fan the flames</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-lies-that-fan-the-flames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 14:04:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-lies-that-fan-the-flames/</guid>
      <description>I hate Nationalism. The damage it wrought in Europe in the twentieth century should have inoculated us all against it, but, once again, it has raised its ugly head. In Scotland, it has become a virulent force and made many converts in the last ten years.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;I do not hate Scottish Nationalists on principle. Those who want Scotland to leave the UK are entitled to their opinion, and I respect those who say that that is what they want, no matter the consequences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Collective Narcissism of MyScotland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-collective-narcissism-of-myscotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 10:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-collective-narcissism-of-myscotland/</guid>
      <description>The SNP is certainly not a party in the conventional sense.&#xA;It is a post-national movement that defines itself by creating enemies and enmities. It tears through Scottish society, because it sees Scotland very differently from the rest of us. It is an ugly, frightening imagination of our country that is created through collective narcissism.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Narcissism is the inability to distinguish self from an internalised ideal. It is pathological, unhealthy and dangerous.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Ross: A leader I believe in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/douglas-ross-a-leader-i-believe-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 13:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/douglas-ross-a-leader-i-believe-in/</guid>
      <description>I have never, under any leader, felt more positive about our chances of winning the next Holyrood Election.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;I believe Douglas Ross is a political nuclear weapon that can not only strike fear into the Scottish National Party, but can stabilise this country financially and restore the power to the people, from a centralist Government in Edinburgh.&#xA;Living in South Lanarkshire, for me, Edinburgh often feels 550 miles away from home, while London feels 30 miles away.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gardening Section</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-gardening-section/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 11:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-gardening-section/</guid>
      <description>When the history of the last decade in Scotland is written, the role played by the Scottish Green Party will come in for special criticism. I had never really thought much about the Green Party. While serving around the world in the Army, I had formed a hazy impression of them as well-meaning eco-eccentrics, the recipients of the none-of-the-above vote at elections and recently led by Caroline Lucas, who seemed to punch above her weight, and occasionally say something sensible on Question Time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devolution has failed: Abolish Holyrood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/devolution-has-failed-abolish-holyrood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 12:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/devolution-has-failed-abolish-holyrood/</guid>
      <description>How much does it cost to change a lightbulb at Holyrood?&#xA;A few quid perhaps? Maybe ten or twenty quid at a stretch? No… in fact it turns out it costs £357 to change a lightbulb at the Scottish parliament building. Some £1.75 Million was spent on upgrading lights in the devolved assemblies’ debating chamber in 2016-7, working out at an astonishing £357 apiece.&#xA;That same year, costs ranged from £25.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Great Education Blame Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-great-education-blame-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 22:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-great-education-blame-game/</guid>
      <description>The heart-breaking stories flooding social media yesterday, demonstrated a scandalous truth: that the life chances of many Scottish children are doomed, regardless of individual effort and ability. They evaporated the illusion of free will, the idea that through grit and determination you can transcend the disadvantages of multiple deprivation and poor schooling. The outcry has been predictable, from individual pupils and parents, politicians on all sides, and educationalists. The latter group warned months ago that the SQA moderation process was dodgy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When will we ever learn?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-will-we-ever-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 17:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/when-will-we-ever-learn/</guid>
      <description>This morning, like many parents in Scotland, I was up early for results day. A few minutes after 8am, my daughter appeared to relay the news. But, something didn’t seem right. Instead of As, two of her results, for Physics and Computing Science, were Bs.&#xA;My mind went back to her last parent-teacher conference, just as the Coronavirus crisis was starting. Her Computing Science teacher was effusive in praise. ‘I’ll be recommending an A,’ he said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calexenophobia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/calexenophobia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 16:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/calexenophobia/</guid>
      <description>There&#39;s something awry in Scotland. The mood is changing, and nasty bigotry is becoming more mainstream. I love it here, but recently, based purely on the way I sound, I have felt judged and not welcome in the country I call home. And it breaks my heart.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;I have lived in Scotland for four years, and before that I worked here for a few months of the year for four years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Scotland Votes Yes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/if-scotland-votes-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 09:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/if-scotland-votes-yes/</guid>
      <description>This article was written on September 11, 2014, a few days before the Scottish Independence Referendum. It is just one of many possible pasts or futures. Let me know what you think would have happened in the comments.&#xA;On September 18, 2014, Scotland votes &#39;yes&#39; to independence by 51%. Independence supporters claimed they wanted a more democratic system, but now 49% of the country is living under a system they don&#39;t want.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freedom for Galloway</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/freedom-for-galloway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 15:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/freedom-for-galloway/</guid>
      <description>Commentary by Jamie Blackett&#xA;Do you know the Mull of Galloway? The chances are that you don’t; even people who live in Galloway have probably never been there, unless they have a passion for sea birds, or lighthouses. I can recommend it for these two things, plus the seascape, but mainly as a way of exploring one’s inner sense of Britishness. There, standing on the southern-most tip of Scotland, gazing across an empty Irish Sea, once the nexus of trade in these islands for early Britons, you get the sense that, having travelled miles to be somewhere really isolated, you have actually located the centre point of the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Have We Done To Deserve This?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-have-we-done-to-deserve-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 13:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/what-have-we-done-to-deserve-this/</guid>
      <description>Commentary by Jill Stephenson&#xA;First a couple of definitions.&#xA;‘We’ are the good, solid people of Scotland who voted to remain in the UK in 2014.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;‘We’ were relieved, rather than triumphalist, about having won the referendum.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;‘We’ didn’t rub the losers’ noses in it but tried to appease them. ‘We’ sat back and let the UK government make concessions to the side that had lost.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;‘We’ believed Salmond and Sturgeon when they repeatedly told us that the referendum was a ‘once in a generation’, ‘once in a lifetime’ event.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunak skelps the Nationalists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/sunak-skelps-the-nationalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 21:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/sunak-skelps-the-nationalists/</guid>
      <description>Commentary by Tommi Kerr.&#xA;On Wednesday afternoon, the Chancellor of Exchequer, Rishi Sunak, delivered a typically impressive performance in the House of Commons. Outlining the next phase of governmental support for the British people, he spoke passionately about protecting livelihoods before announcing an imaginative set of measures intended to kick-start the UK economy.&#xA;The&amp;nbsp;speech&amp;nbsp;– entitled ‘A Plan for Jobs’ – contained several notable soundbites. The measures themselves were eye-catching, with a floundering hospitality sector receiving special attention in the form of a VAT reduction and a new policy dubbed ‘Eat Out to Help Out’ – cue much innuendo on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The SNP’s Orwellian Outrage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snps-orwellian-outrage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 11:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snps-orwellian-outrage/</guid>
      <description>A guest editorial by Matt M.&#xA;For some time now, the SNP, under Nicola Sturgeon, has attempted to portray itself as a paragon of virtue and truth. The party proclaims itself as anti-discriminatory, anti-racist, anti-sectarian, and anti all-things-objectionable-to-a-tolerant-and-civilised-society. Defender of the bastion of Jocktopia.&#xA;When Nicola Sturgeon strutted her rant at George Square last December, she advised us of her ‘vision’ for Scotland. Apparently, the ‘New Scotland’ is to be open, welcoming, tolerant and inclusive (no Tories please!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religion should guide, not divide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/religion-should-guide-not-divide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 15:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/religion-should-guide-not-divide/</guid>
      <description>A guest editorial by James Bundy. In a recent commentary, ‘Ireland’s past is not Scotland’s future’, Damien Scott talks about his upbringing in a mixed Catholic-Protestant home. Damien says he is now an atheist and that as religious belief has dwindled in Scotland, politics has replaced it as an article of faith. In effect, he says politics is Scotland’s new religion.&#xA;However, as a practising Catholic, I believe my faith does play a fundamental role in shaping my political beliefs, including my view that Scotland is better off as part of the United Kingdom, and that the world is better off because of the United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would you like a foot rub too, Nicola?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/would-you-like-a-foot-rub-too-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/would-you-like-a-foot-rub-too-nicola/</guid>
      <description>When will the opposition parties in Scotland learn to fight? Today I was appalled to see yet another weak and compliant message from Jackson Carlaw, leader of the Scottish Conservatives, praising the Nationalists for their response to COVID-19.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;https://twitter.com/themajorityscot/status/1278663688346570753 This comes on the heels of an earlier tweet where he did the same:&#xA;https://twitter.com/ScotTories/status/1247056001079095296 Confidence in the First Minister? W.T.A.F.&#xA;Jackson, a wee clue: they are not your friends. They are Nationalists who are destroying our country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola, close the Glasgow and Lanarkshire borders now!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-close-the-glasgow-and-lanarkshire-borders-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-close-the-glasgow-and-lanarkshire-borders-now/</guid>
      <description>Over the past 24 hours there&#39;s been quite a bit of discussion about closing the border from England, led by a shameless front-page headline in The National.&#xA;There&#39;s even a poll with over 5000 signatures that claims trips from England to Scoland are &#39;international&#39;...&#xA;There is about to be a massive second wave of this new virus in England due to Tory ineptitude. The borders of both Scotland and Wales should be closed to all but essential traffic ie commerce.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ireland&#39;s past is not Scotland&#39;s future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/irelands-past-is-not-scotlands-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 21:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/irelands-past-is-not-scotlands-future/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest editorial by Damien Scott, founder of Scottish Opposition Forum. It has been 22 years since the Good Friday Agreement was reached. After the 1997 General Election and the subsequent referendum on reconvening the Scottish Parliament for the first time in nearly 300 years, the April 1998 event was probably the third earliest political moment that I remember. At my tender age, I didn’t fully understand the details of the peace accord, but I knew it was a significant moment in the history of our country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon is ‘socially-distancing’ herself from Scottish parents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-is-socially-distancing-herself-from-scottish-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 15:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-is-socially-distancing-herself-from-scottish-parents/</guid>
      <description>In a previous contribution I wrote how the SNP have failed schoolchildren of all ages and stages of progress, with slipping standards. The Scottish Survey of Literacy and Numeracy (SSLN) found that only 49% of 13/14 year olds were performing &#34;very well&#34; or &#34;well&#34; in 2016, down from 55% in 2014 and 64% in 2012. It is against that backdrop that the SNP need a bolder drive and ambition to get Scottish school children all of the classroom time they can.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cult of St. Nicola</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-cult-of-st.-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 21:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-cult-of-st.-nicola/</guid>
      <description>The camera shakes. A young child comes into view, the first of many, their gleaming eyes open and eager. They start talking in the coached manner of totalitarian regimes: The children of North Korea would like to say ‘thank you’ to our Dear Leader. We are so grateful, thank you for always keeping us safe, working so hard, for being strong for us. Thank you for caring for every individual life and for always thinking about the children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five times Scottish Nationalists bullied the media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-times-scottish-nationalists-bullied-the-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 19:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/five-times-scottish-nationalists-bullied-the-media/</guid>
      <description>#5. The Sun pulled an article about the Health Secretary’s complacency…during a pandemic Despite being months into the Coronavirus pandemic crisis, when frontline workers are still not being routinely tested and PPE shortages are still troubling, the Scottish Health Secretary, Jeane Freeman, had time in her schedule to tweet she would chase up ASDA for Nationalist journalist Angela Haggerty’s groceries.&#xA;This, rightly, attracted much scorn and derision. The Sun ran a perfectly legitimate article, which they then deleted, leaving little trace that this story ever existed - an airbrush job the Ministry of Truth would be proud of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon: Bigotry in a Smart Suit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeon-bigotry-in-a-smart-suit/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, I was talking to a female ex-Labour supporter, and new Nationalist. While claiming she was &#39;for social justice&#39;, she said that she was all for anyone being Scottish, except for JK Rowling. When I asked why, she told me that Rowling should be excluded because of her political views. Whatever you think of Ms Rowling, or transgender activism, this woman, who presumably thinks she is a decent person, told me straight up that someone with a different political opinion from her has no place in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nicola Sturgeon&#39;s Five Biggest Failures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeons-five-biggest-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 21:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/nicola-sturgeons-five-biggest-failures/</guid>
      <description>#5 She deprived 300,000 children of their new hospital Edinburgh&#39;s new Sick Children&#39;s Hospital was&amp;nbsp;supposed to open at the end of 2012.&amp;nbsp; You didn’t misread that: it&#39;s just one example of the level of incompetence we must live with under the SNP in Scotland.&#xA;The project has been so delayed it has even&amp;nbsp;outlived three previous health secretaries&amp;nbsp;who were looking after it, making Jeane Freeman the fourth. &amp;nbsp;I hear you all breath sighs of relief at that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Not A &#34;Unionist&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/why-im-not-a-unionist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 12:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/why-im-not-a-unionist/</guid>
      <description>One of the main techniques extremist groups like Nationalists use to make themselves appear normal is to label their opponents something they would like them to be and then attack that label.&#xA;By labelling their opponents as “Unionists” or “Yoons” they associate them with Union Jacks, British bulldogs, Churchill, and The Queen.&#xA;(Of course the Union that the Nationalists almost always imagine is English — they never include Northern Ireland or Wales, or the Scottish people who are part of Britain.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
