<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>George Galloway on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/george-galloway/</link>
    <description>Recent content in George Galloway on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 21:14:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/george-galloway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about George</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/lets-talk-about-george/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 21:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/lets-talk-about-george/</guid>
      <description>As the election enters its final week, All For Unity has come under sustained attack from people on Twitter, led by Tory party activists, who, scared of losing list seats, have briefed candidates to launch personal attacks on George Galloway.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;To be honest, I was initially sceptical about George too. However, I had been awestruck by his debating skills in the US Senate, his passion in 2014 on the pro-UK side, and his commitment now to strategies that could beat the SNP and beat back the ugly and tiresome Nationalism that has brought Scotland to its knees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polls, insults and manifestos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/polls-insults-and-manifestos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 20:51:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/polls-insults-and-manifestos/</guid>
      <description>They say, with penetrating accuracy, that once you become a parent you are only as happy as your least happy child. And, sad to say, since we got the Alliance for Unity going last year it has been like having an extra child. The party’s triumphs and disasters have produced the same reaction in me as my children’s and I find myself worrying like a parent about our progress.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;The anxiety to start with was not finding enough people of sufficient calibre to join us; then it was that the Electoral Commission would find excuses to keep turning down our application to be a political party until beyond polling day; then it was that we would simply be ignored by everyone; then it was that we would never feature in any polls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A week is a long time in politics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-week-is-a-long-time-in-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 21:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/a-week-is-a-long-time-in-politics/</guid>
      <description>“A week is a long time in politics” is a trite opening sentence but it has been true this week, as Salmond’s forced entry into the race has left things ‘all changed, changed utterly’ as WB Yeats wrote 105 years ago in a rather similar context. It is what we have feared all along: the formation of a ‘Nationalist Front’ and a creeping Ulsterisation of Scottish politics with Salmond already talking about ‘street protests’ as part of their campaign for secession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The campaign starts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-campaign-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 14:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-campaign-starts/</guid>
      <description>George Galloway and I launch our campaign by filming a ‘Potemkin rally’ in the pub carpark – all that we can do during lockdown.&#xA;We are met by the village loudmouth, ostentatiously masked by a black scarf against the Covid on the cold March breeze. “What’s going on here? Did you no see the saltires as you drove in? We don’t want you and your Union here.” He patrols the one street in the village while we are filming, just in case any ‘Yoons’ think about joining in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: The SNP framed Salmond</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 03:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-the-snp-framed-salmond/</guid>
      <description>In a livestream broadcast on All for Unity’s (the new name for Alliance for Unity) social media channels, George Galloway doesn’t mince his words when talking about the Sturgeon-Salmond scandal.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;Comparing Sturgeon’s government to a banana republic, he starts by talking about the malicious fraud prosecution of administrators over the Rangers bankruptcy by the Crown Office.&#xA;£24 million of Scottish taxpayers money is about to be paid out because of a malicious prosecution mounted by the Scottish Law officer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway Straight Answers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 13:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-straight-answers/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with Scotland Matters, The Majority presents a video interview series with George Galloway, covering his return to Scottish politics, his plans for Alliance For Unity, tactical voting and his views on Nicola Sturgeon. Watch them all.&#xA;#1 - Why have you come back to Scottish Politics?&#xD;https://youtu.be/iSLyTD9Cu1Q&#xD;#2 - Why is the UK important to you?&#xD;https://youtu.be/skM3XRzmCVc&#xD;#3 - Given your past causes why should people support you now?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: Salmond’s fat arse, Bun fights at the OK Corral, and The Mother of All Scandals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-salmonds-fat-arse-bun-fights-at-the-ok-corral-and-the-mother-of-all-scandals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 20:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-salmonds-fat-arse-bun-fights-at-the-ok-corral-and-the-mother-of-all-scandals/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CcIPr3AOGhQ&#xD;In his weekly broadcast, George Galloway, leader of the fledgling Alliance For Unity Party, covers many of the issues in Scottish politics today. We have transcribed the best parts for you.&#xA;#1 Significant Labour figure to join Alliance For Unity We are building a stable of parliamentary candidates that are really thoroughbreds and I can&#39;t tell you who right now, but I have been talking for the last day or two to a very prominent twice Labour party parliamentary candidate about joining us on the lists for the Holyrood elections in May.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Choice: Civilization or the Tribe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-choice-civilization-or-the-tribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 18:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-choice-civilization-or-the-tribe/</guid>
      <description>Four of the candidates who will be standing for the Alliance for Unity, in a bid to maximise the anti-Separatist vote in next May’s crucial Scottish Parliament elections, have delivered Monday evening broadcasts which can be found on You Tube.&#xA;George Galloway, Jamie Blackett, David Griffiths and Alan Sked spoke with clarity and conviction about their formative experiences. An ardent socialist, a conservative-minded businessman, a Leaver and a Remainer, as well as two supporters of Glasgow’s highly competitive football clubs, can be found among the four.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Galloway: Three Reasons Against Separation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-three-reasons-against-separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 22:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/galloway-three-reasons-against-separation/</guid>
      <description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MfzzO_9YN9k&#xD;It’s only been a few weeks since George Galloway announced his return to Scottish politics, with the aim of taking on Scottish Nationalists in the 2021 Scottish elections. In that time, he has formed a new party @Alliance4Unity, which has gained over 7400 Twitter followers in a week, and received over 1800 letters from would-be candidates (which he says he is having some difficulty processing).&#xA;Today, he appeared live on YouTube and Twitter&amp;nbsp;to discuss his views and his new party, citing three main reasons he opposes Separation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
