<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Humza Yousaf on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/humza-yousaf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Humza Yousaf on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 17:52:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/humza-yousaf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The SNP has never had a mandate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-never-had-a-mandate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 17:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-snp-has-never-had-a-mandate/</guid>
      <description>It is a commonly touted assertion of the SNP that all elections, Westminster or devolved, will be referendums on independence and if they achieve a majority of some kind then this will give them a mandate for independence. But what does ‘mandate’ actually mean?&amp;nbsp;&#xA;A standard definition (via Google) of a mandate is:&#xA;The authority to carry out a policy, regarded as given by the electorate to a party or candidate that wins an election.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After the earthquake, a tsunami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/after-the-earthquake-a-tsunami/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/after-the-earthquake-a-tsunami/</guid>
      <description>It’s said that before a tsunami strikes there are major warning signs to look out for that should alert the public to the forthcoming catastrophe. Warning signs such as an earthquake at sea, or the tide suddenly going out, are usually enough to galvanise the inhabitants of neighbouring coastal towns to immediately head for the high ground.&#xA;Political tsunamis have striking similarities to the real thing. For example, there were many early warning signs before the 2015 General Election that alerted all pro-UK parties in Scotland to the very real possibility that they were going to be swept away by a gigantic nationalist tidal wave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The war on your thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-war-on-your-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 20:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/the-war-on-your-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>The SNP’s obsession with being perceived as morally superior is the glue they collectively sniff before composing any public messaging. No matter the issue, rest assured that it cannot possibly be the SNP’s fault. Gone are the days of accountability, gone are the days of owning up to something and the days of transparency are but a faint memory.&#xA;Following the resounding ‘once in a generation’ 2014 referendum defeat, what did the SNP do?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
