<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Richard Leonard on The Majority</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/richard-leonard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Richard Leonard on The Majority</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 13:32:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/richard-leonard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Will ye go, laddie, go</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/will-ye-go-laddie-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 13:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/will-ye-go-laddie-go/</guid>
      <description>Richard Leonard, Scottish Labour’s leader, has now been in the job for three years, during which time he has presided over multiple election defeats. In the European elections in May 2019, the party slumped to fifth in Scotland, polling less than 10% of the vote. The party then fell from seven seats to one in November’s General Election.&#xA;A YouGov poll for The Times puts support for Labour at 14 per cent in Holyrood’s constituency and list vote.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would you like a foot rub too, Nicola?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/would-you-like-a-foot-rub-too-nicola/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 16:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/would-you-like-a-foot-rub-too-nicola/</guid>
      <description>When will the opposition parties in Scotland learn to fight? Today I was appalled to see yet another weak and compliant message from Jackson Carlaw, leader of the Scottish Conservatives, praising the Nationalists for their response to COVID-19.&amp;nbsp;&#xA;This comes on the heels of an earlier tweet where he did the same:&#xA;Confidence in the First Minister? W.T.A.F.&#xA;Jackson, a wee clue: they are not your friends. They are Nationalists who are destroying our country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wanted: a worthy opponent to Nicola Sturgeon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/wanted-a-worthy-opponent-to-nicola-sturgeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 17:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/wanted-a-worthy-opponent-to-nicola-sturgeon/</guid>
      <description>https://stephendaisley.com/2020/06/15/wanted-a-worthy-opponent-to-nicola-sturgeon/&#xD;Stephen Daisley, writing on his blog, says that frustration is rising as Scottish Nationalists fail to deliver results after 13 years in power.&#xA;Three terms of Nationalist rule have produced little of substance and on education and health we have seen progress stall and even go into reverse. Meanwhile, sizeable reserves of political capital, parliamentary time and government resources have gone into a constitutional war of attrition. What exactly about the past 13 years would make anyone want another five?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
